<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<book lang="en">
	<bookinfo>
		<title>Gentile</title>
		<subtitle>a study of the non-Jew in Torah</subtitle>
		<author>
			<firstname>James</firstname>
			<surname>Gosnell</surname>
			<affiliation>
				<address><email>jamesgosnell@gmail.com</email></address>
			</affiliation>
		</author>
		<copyright>
			<year>2015</year>
			<holder>Copyright James Gosnell. All rights reserved.</holder>
		</copyright>
		<abstract>
			<para>a study of the non-Jew in Torah</para>
		</abstract>
	</bookinfo>
	<preface>
		<title>Preface</title>
		<para>This is much of my life's work regarding the non-Jew in <emphasis>
				<indexterm>
					<primary>Torah</primary>
				</indexterm>
			</emphasis> from my own personal study. I would like to share with everyone what I've
			found. These answers were received from my sojourn in <emphasis>Torah</emphasis>. I
			think many of us ask questions yet many of us get bogged down and never find definitive
			answers, which demoralize many of us to the point of giving up or disbelief. I like to
			think this book will convey the things I found that I believe are incumbent on every
			human-being to know. It would be a personal tragedy if I did not convey it for
			posterity.</para>
		<para>I will use Hebrew words and phrases to help convey the original wisdom in context. Any
			translations into English are my own unless stated otherwise. Transliterated words will
			be italicised. I try to use only original <emphasis>Torah</emphasis> words, but when I
			deviate, it will most likely be due to problems in English words and their understanding
			that I need to rectify. Translated words from their original Hebrew often come out as
			vulgar. I do my best to not be common in my language. There is a balance that must be
			met between stooping language down for the simple man to understand and between giving
			the unadulterated wisdom. I think that balance is to use transliterated Hebrew nouns at
			the very least. If you're reading this book, then that means you must have the aptitude
			to learn new ideas and new words. We then might as well learn actual Hebrew words in
			context, rather than a translation that usually bastardizes the original meaning and
			wisdom of the word and any other negative side-effects a non-Hebrew language would do to
			describe Hebraic ideas and concepts.</para>
		<para>For most of the book, I'll be using the term <emphasis>bnei Yisrael</emphasis> which
			is the Hebrew translation for <emphasis>children of Israel</emphasis>. It's common today
			to refer to <emphasis>bnei Yisrael</emphasis> as "Jews" or the Jewish People, but for
			the sake of clarity, I'll be using <emphasis>bnei Yisrael</emphasis> instead, which is
			usually the phrase used in <emphasis>Torah</emphasis>.</para>
		<para>This book will not be received well by many people, including rabbis. They will disagree
			with the book, but be unable to give a clear proof why, or at the least, give straw-man
			arguments. An example, would be arguing I'm wrong about the attributes I give to the
			word <emphasis>bnei Noach</emphasis>, when really, the arguer is referring to
				<emphasis>goyim</emphasis>. Unfortunately for them and their listeners,
				<emphasis>bnei Noach</emphasis> and <emphasis>goyim</emphasis> are two different
				<emphasis>gedarim</emphasis>/categories of non-Jews. It's comparing apples and
			oranges as explained later in the book. Many do not understand the
				<emphasis>gedarim</emphasis> of non-Jews within Torah and it leads many astray and
			has caused much contention in the world. This book helps to rectify that. If I give my
			opinion about a matter, I usually preface the statement with "It appears to me" or "In
			my opinion". I also ask questions that I would like to know answers to. Please contact
			me through email.</para>
		<para>This book is organic and being updated regularly. Instead of having a number of editions, I
			will be using a version number, similar to that of computer software and only use
			numbered editions when printing. The source files for the book are housed in a version
			controlled repository that is constantly being added to, updated, fixed and processed
			into multiple media formats.</para>
	</preface>
	<xi:include href="intro.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"/>
	<xi:include href="umot_haolam.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"/>
	<xi:include href="chasidei_umot_haolam.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"/>
	<xi:include href="m_chasidei_umot_haolam.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"/>
	<glossary>
		<title>Glossary</title>
		<para>A Glossary to help encourage you to know original Hebrew terms for better
			understanding, clarity, and to come out of vulgarity(Zephaniah 3:9)</para>
		<glossdiv>
			<title>Hebrew Phrases</title>
			<glossentry>
				<glossterm>goy</glossterm>
				<glossdef>
					<para>a non-Jew idolater</para>
				</glossdef>
			</glossentry>
			<glossentry>
				<glossterm>sheva mitzvot bnei Noach</glossterm>
				<glossdef>
					<para>the seven laws of the Children of Noah</para>
				</glossdef>
			</glossentry>
			<glossentry>
				<glossterm>Torah shebikhtav</glossterm>
				<glossdef>
					<para>Torah that is in writing; the written Torah; the first five books of the
						Chumash(Genesis, Exodus, etc.)</para>
				</glossdef>
			</glossentry>
			<glossentry>
				<glossterm>Torah shebe'alpeh</glossterm>
				<glossdef>
					<para>Torah that is from the mouth; oral Torah; the Torah verbally given by
						Moses on how to do Torah</para>
				</glossdef>
			</glossentry>
			<glossentry>
				<glossterm>Mishnah</glossterm>
				<glossdef>
					<para>the <emphasis>Torah shebe'alpeh</emphasis> that was committed to writing
						for fear of losing it</para>
				</glossdef>
			</glossentry>
			<glossentry>
				<glossterm>Gemara</glossterm>
				<glossdef>
					<para>commentary and exposition to <emphasis>Mishnah</emphasis></para>
				</glossdef>
			</glossentry>
		</glossdiv>
	</glossary>
	<index>
	</index>
</book>
