<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<chapter id="goy">
	<title>Goy</title>
	<para>You've probably heard the term <emphasis>goy</emphasis> used in reference to
			<emphasis>non-Jews</emphasis>.</para>
	<para>Colloquially, the term <emphasis>goy</emphasis> is used to refer to a non-Jew. Students of
		Torah generally do not care too much for modern colloquiallisms in their studies. Therefore,
		we will not be referring to this type of <emphasis>goy</emphasis>. Instead, we will be
		referrring to the <emphasis>goy</emphasis> found in <emphasis>Torah</emphasis>. This is the
			<emphasis>goy stam</emphasis> - the plain <emphasis>goy</emphasis>.</para>
	<para>In <emphasis>Torah shebikhtav</emphasis>, the term <emphasis>goy</emphasis> seems to have a
		neutral connotation, where any negativity toward <emphasis>goy</emphasis> would be implied.
		This may not actually be true, but it seems that way. However, it seems during the time of
		the Prophets and Writings, <emphasis>goyim</emphasis> started getting a bad wrap for being
		primarily idol worshippers. This connotation carried over into the <emphasis>Torah
			sheba'alpeh</emphasis>, where <emphasis>goyim</emphasis> as idolaters were solidified.
		It is only with other qualifiers that <emphasis>goy</emphasis> changes it's idolater
		status.</para>
	<sect1>
		<title><emphasis>Goy</emphasis> and <emphasis>Am</emphasis>: The Difference</title>
		<para>The words <emphasis>goy</emphasis> and <emphasis>am</emphasis> are usually both translated
			as "people" or "nation" and are seemed to be interchangeable. However, that doesn't seem
			to be the case. <emphasis>Goy</emphasis> seems to denote something akin to culture and
			way of life. <emphasis>Am</emphasis> seems to denote physical groups of people that live
			and interact with one another. <emphasis>Bnei Yisrael</emphasis> is referred to as a
			holy <emphasis>goy</emphasis>; often translated as <emphasis>holy nation</emphasis>. -
			הכרמל - מלבים, מאיר ליבוש, 1809-1879</para>
	</sect1>
	<sect1>
		<title>History</title>
		<para>This History of the <emphasis>goy</emphasis></para>
		<para>The etymology of the word from the etymological dictionary</para>
	</sect1>
	<sect1>
		<title>Halacha</title>
		<para>Halachah for the <emphasis>goy</emphasis></para>
		<para>A <emphasis>goy</emphasis> cannot envolve himself in <emphasis>Torah</emphasis>
			study.</para>
		<para>A <emphasis>goy</emphasis> cannot keep shabbat. He cannot even rest or take time to
			rest. He may not create holidays.</para>
		<para>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>And the Gemara explained:</para>
					<para>"An ox of a Jew which gores an ox of a Canaanite is exempt." They say:
						whichever way you turn -- if "his neighbor" is meant specifically, an ox of
						a Canaanite which gores an ox of a Jew should also be exempt; if "his
						neighbor" is not meant specifically, an ox of a Jew which gores an ox of a
						Canaanite should also be liable. Rabbi Abahu said: it is written, "He stood
						and measured the earth; He beheld and drove asunder the nations" -- [God]
						saw that the Sons of Noah [Gentiles] were not fulfilling the Seven
						Commandments they accepted upon themselves, and permitted their property to
						the Jews. Rabbi Jochanan said, it is learnt from here: "He appeared from
						Mount Paran" -- from Mount Paran [the Giving of the Torah] their property
						was permitted to the Jews.</para>
					<para>(Bava Kama 38a)</para>
					<para>To which the Meiri added:</para>
					<blockquote>
						<para>According to what is said in the Gemara, this law applies only to the
							nations which are not restricted by ways of religions and customs, as
							the Gemara said of them, "[God] saw that the Sons of Noah [non-Jews]
							were not fulfilling the Seven Commandments <ulink
								url="http://www.talkreason.org/articles/meiri.cfm#20">[20]</ulink>
							they accepted upon themselves, so He permitted their property to the
							Jews," as long as they are obliged by these commandments -- therefore,
							those [non-Jews] who fulfill the Seven Commandments should be treated by
							us as we are treated by them, and we should not favor ourselves in
							judgment; now it is unnecessary to specify that this is also the case
							concerning the nations restricted by ways of religions and
							customs.</para>
						<para>(Beit ha-Bechirah on Bava Kama 37b)</para>
					</blockquote>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</para>
	</sect1>
	<sect1>
		<title>Responsa</title>
		<para><emphasis role="bold">Statement:</emphasis> The <emphasis>goy</emphasis> means all
			non-Jews</para>
		<para><emphasis role="bold">Response:</emphasis> The <emphasis>goy</emphasis> is different
			than other non-Jews. For example the <emphasis>goy</emphasis> cannot give charity to the
				<emphasis>bnei Yisrael</emphasis> and have a poor <emphasis>bne Yisrael</emphasis>
			accept it. However, a <emphasis>ben Noach</emphasis> who keeps the <emphasis>sheva
				mitzvot bnei Noach</emphasis> can give charity and it is received. Therefore,
				<emphasis>goyim</emphasis> and <emphasis>bnei Noach</emphasis> are not the
			same.</para>
		<para><emphasis role="bold">Statement:</emphasis> The <emphasis>goy</emphasis> is a superset
			of non-Jews</para>
	</sect1>
</chapter>
