<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
	<chapter id="bnei_noach">
	<title>Children of Noah</title>
	<subtitle>בני נח - Bnei Noach</subtitle>
	<para><emphasis>Bnei Noach</emphasis> are the children of Noah. <emphasis>haShem Elokim</emphasis>
		commanded all <emphasis>bnei Noach</emphasis> to keep the <emphasis>sheva mitzvot bnei
			Noach</emphasis>. The rainbow is a sign of that covenant. It's an eternal covenant. As
		long as a society keeps to the covenant, <emphasis>haShem Elokim</emphasis> will not destroy
		that society.</para>
	<para>All of humanity are <emphasis>bnei Noach</emphasis>. <emphasis>Bnei Yisrael</emphasis> has a
		distinction from the merit of Avraham and are not classified as <emphasis>bnei
			Noach</emphasis> even though technically they are also descended from Noah.<footnote
			id="Nedarim_31a">
			<para>Nedarim 31a</para>
		</footnote></para>
	<para>Therefore, whenever the term <emphasis>bnei Noach</emphasis> is used, this is referring
		those that are not <emphasis>bnei Yisrael</emphasis>. I currently do not know if
			<emphasis>gerim</emphasis> are <emphasis>bnei Noach</emphasis>.
			<emphasis>Gerim</emphasis> are attached to <emphasis>bnei Yisrael</emphasis> and are
		described as being part of <emphasis>klal Yisrael</emphasis>. It appears to me that
			<emphasis>gerim</emphasis> would then also be from the merit of Avraham and set apart
		with with <emphasis>bnei Yisrael</emphasis>.<footnoteref linkend="Nedarim_31a"/></para>
	<para><emphasis>Bnei Noach</emphasis> may give the holiest of offerings; the burnt offering. The
		burnt offering is the only offering they may give as <emphasis>bnei Noach</emphasis> proper.
		It appears to me, that this is because once <emphasis>bnei Noach</emphasis> give a proper
		burnt offering, they enter a new status as a <emphasis>ger</emphasis>, which is someone who
		is now sojourning into a relationship with <emphasis>haShem</emphasis>.</para>
	<para><emphasis>Bnei Noach</emphasis> may or may not emanate from <emphasis>klipot
			nogah</emphasis>. If <emphasis>bnei Noach</emphasis> keep the <emphasis>sheva mitzvot
			bnei Noach</emphasis> for any other reason than for the sake of heaven, they emanate not
		from <emphasis>klipot nogah</emphasis>, but rather from the three impure
			<emphasis>klipot</emphasis> where no good exists. They then do not receive a portion in
			<emphasis>Olam haBah</emphasis>. However, if <emphasis>bnei Noach</emphasis> keep the
			<emphasis>sheva mitzvot bnei Noach</emphasis> for the sake of Heaven, they emanate from
			<emphasis>klipot nogah</emphasis> where there is good and evil. They do receive a
		portion in <emphasis>Olam haBa</emphasis>. One must be attached to the Source of
			<emphasis>Olam haBa</emphasis>.</para>
	<para><emphasis>Bnei Noach</emphasis> are made in the image of <emphasis>haShem
			Elokim</emphasis>:Tosephos YomTov on Avos 3:14 in explanation of the saying of Rabbi
		Akiva in the Mishna there "beloved is Man who is created in the Divine Image" as this was
		also said with reference to Bnai Noach - and according to what the Rambam writes in the Laws
		of Kings. See there.</para>
	<sect1>
		<title>History</title>
		<para>This History of the <emphasis>bnei Noach</emphasis></para>
	</sect1>
	<sect1>
		<title>Halacha</title>
		<sect2>
			<title>No Eating the Limb of a Live Animal</title>
			<para>No Eating Limbs of a Live Animal</para>
		</sect2>
		<sect2>
			<title>No Murder</title>
			<para>No Murder</para>
			<para>May not flee to a city of refuge. <emphasis>Bnei Yisrael</emphasis> will not
				receive him.</para>
		</sect2>
		<sect2>
			<title>No Stealing</title>
			<para>No Stealing</para>
		</sect2>
		<sect2>
			<title>No Blasphemy</title>
			<para>No Blasphemy</para>
		</sect2>
		<sect2>
			<title>No Strange Worship</title>
			<para>No Strange Worship</para>
		</sect2>
		<sect2>
			<title>No Illicit Relationships</title>
			<para>No Illicit Relationships</para>
		</sect2>
		<sect2>
			<title>No Failure to Establish a Court</title>
			<para>No Failure to Establish a Court</para>
		</sect2>
	</sect1>
	<sect1>
		<title>Responsa</title>
		<para><emphasis role="bold">Statement:</emphasis> The <emphasis>bnei Noach</emphasis> must stay
				<emphasis>bnei Noach</emphasis></para>
		<para><emphasis role="bold">Response:</emphasis>
			<emphasis>Bnei Noach</emphasis> can give the holiest of offerings, the burnt offering,
			which is an action of total submission and transformation</para>
	</sect1>
</chapter>
