<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
	<chapter id="pious_people_of_the_world">
	<title>Pious People of the World</title>
	<subtitle>חסדי עמות העלם - Chasidei Umot haOlam</subtitle>
	<para><emphasis>Chassidei Umot haOlam</emphasis> are not attached to <emphasis>bnei
			Yisrael</emphasis> like <emphasis>gerim</emphasis>. They are still attached to their
		host nation and are held hostage in a way(see Rebbe's Sichot on this matter). They would of
		been with <emphasis>klal Yisrael</emphasis> during <emphasis>maten Torah</emphasis> but
		their host nations held them hostage. Spiritually, they are attached to <emphasis>klal
			Yisrael</emphasis>, but not physically and do not gain those blessings. Those who are
		physically attached by living among <emphasis>bnei Yisrael</emphasis> are referred to as
			<emphasis>ger toshav</emphasis>. Their host nations receive blessings from them.</para>
	<para><emphasis>Chassidei Umot haOlam</emphasis> may give a burnt offering.</para>
	<para><emphasis>Chassidei Umot haOlam</emphasis> are worthy of the crown of Torah. Teffilin is a
		personal crown of Torah.</para>
	<para><emphasis>Chassidei Umot haOlam</emphasis> have animal souls that emanate from
			<emphasis>klipat nogah</emphasis>. <emphasis>Klipot nogah</emphasis> contains a mixture
		of good and evil and is the same place where <emphasis>bnei Yisrael</emphasis> animal souls
		and clean animal souls originate.</para>
	<para>It appears to me that it may be <emphasis>Chassidei Umot haOlam</emphasis> that do more
		than the <emphasis>sheva mitzvot haShem</emphasis> are like ones that do
			<emphasis>mitzvot</emphasis> but are not commanded, similar to <emphasis>bnei Noach
			stam</emphasis> that do and are not commanded.</para>
	<sect1>
		<title>History</title>
		<para>Pious means: use note text from R'Turen</para>
		<para>Umot means: peoples</para>
		<para>haOlam means: over the horizon</para>
		<para>Rav said: Avraham our Patriarch fulfilled the entire Torah, as it is stated: "Because
			Avraham hearkened to My voice and kept My charge, My mitzvot, My satutes adnd My Torahs"
			Gen 26:5. Rav Shimi bar Khiyya said to Rav: And say seven mitzvot(bnei Noach). But isn't
			there also circumcision? The Gemara says: and say the seven mitzvot and circumcision.
			Rav said to him: If so, why do I say Abraham kept: My mitzvot and my Torah? Rav said,
			and some say Rav Ashi said: Abraham our Patriarch fulfilled even the joining of cooked
			foods, as it is stated: My Torahs: Torah sheba'alpeh and Torah shebikhtav. - Yoma
			28b</para>
		<para>It appears to me that both opinions are correct and do not contradict. How could
				<emphasis>Avraham</emphasis> have kept <emphasis>mitzvot</emphasis> that were yet to
			be commanded? He did them through the <emphasis>Torah of Shem v'Ever</emphasis>.
				<emphasis>Avraham</emphasis> was the first <emphasis>ger tzedek</emphasis>.</para>
		<para>The etymology of the words from the etymological dictionary.</para>
	</sect1>
	<sect1>
		<title>Halacha</title>
		<para><emphasis>Chassidei umot haOlam</emphasis> are the same as keepers of the seven laws of
				<emphasis>bnei Noach</emphasis>, except they keep the seven laws because
				<emphasis>haShem</emphasis> gave them via Moshe and Torah. There is a disagreement
			if it's because the seven are in Torah or if it's because Moshe received and gave them
			again.</para>
	</sect1>
	<sect1>
		<title>Responsa</title>
		<para><emphasis role="bold">Statement:</emphasis> The <emphasis>goy</emphasis> means all
			non-Jews</para>
	</sect1>
</chapter>
