<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<chapter id="ger">
	<title>Sojourners</title>
	<subtitle>גרם - Gerim</subtitle>
	<para>The <emphasis>ger</emphasis> is a sojourner. A <emphasis>ger</emphasis> can be <emphasis>bnei
		Yisrael</emphasis> or not.<footnote><para>"I am a stranger and a sojourner with you: give me a possession of a buryingplace with you, that I may bury my dead out of my sight." - Genesis 23:4 KJV</para></footnote> The <emphasis>ger</emphasis> without any other qualifier is
		almost always referring to <emphasis>ger tzedek</emphasis> in
		<emphasis>halachah</emphasis>.<footnote><para>Hilchot Assurot Machalot 11:8</para></footnote></para>
	<para>The <emphasis>ger</emphasis> is anyone who attaches themselves to Godliness in some way
		and is not an idol-worshipper. This attachment could be by Torah, by interacting and
		clinging to <emphasis>bnei Yisrael</emphasis>, or by contemplating on the true nature of
			<emphasis>haShem</emphasis> and his wisdom. The <emphasis>ger</emphasis> is a sojourner.
		He may or may not have the greatest of intentions.</para>
	<para><emphasis>Ger</emphasis> is often seen translated into English as the
			<emphasis>stranger</emphasis>. In Torah, he is the <emphasis>stranger</emphasis> in the
		gate, the person that attaches himself to <emphasis>bnei Yisrael</emphasis>. However, this
		is not an accurate translation. <emphasis>Stranger</emphasis> in Hebrew is actually the
			<emphasis>zer</emphasis>. <emphasis>Ger</emphasis> is more accurately translated as
			<emphasis>sojourner</emphasis>.</para>
	<sect1>
		<title>History</title>
		<para>The first time we see <emphasis>ger</emphasis> is in Genesis</para>
		<para>The etymology of the word from the etymological dictionary.</para>
	</sect1>
	<sect1>
		<title>Halacha</title>
		<para>In <emphasis>Torah shebikhtav</emphasis>, <emphasis>ger</emphasis> usually refers to a
				<emphasis>ger toshav</emphasis>. In <emphasis>Torah shebe'alpeh</emphasis>,
				<emphasis>ger</emphasis> usually refers a <emphasis>ger tzedek</emphasis>.</para>
	</sect1>
	<sect1>
		<title>Responsa</title>
		<para><emphasis role="bold">Statement:</emphasis> The Ger Toshav doesn't exist today</para>
		<para><emphasis role="bold">Statement:</emphasis> A <emphasis>ger toshav</emphasis> is still
			a <emphasis>goy</emphasis></para>
		<para><emphasis role="bold">Response:</emphasis> Hilchot Maachalot Assurot 11:8:"when we say
			plainly 'goy', we mean an idolator".Is Hilchot Maachalot Assurot 11:8 a true statement
			Jacob?The response you've made to my argument is an ad hominem(personal attack) and is
			not a valid argument; they are obfuscations. You also have yet to disprove any of the
			other arguments I've said. Concerning the Issurei Biah 14:7:You say that the ger toshav
			is a goy even after he swears off idolatry.Using that logic, when Issurei Biah 13:3 says
			a ger tzedek is a goy as well, you're still able to call him a goy:"When a goy desires
			to enter into the covenant..."However, a ger tzedek is no longer a goy, lest you say all
			converts cannot keep shabbat, study Torah, etc. per Hilchot Melachim 10:9 "A goy cannot
			study Torah...". Following the rule in set theory, a subset follows all the attributes
			of its superset, so when you call a ger a subset of goy, this cannot be the case.</para>
		<para>For instance:set all integers: {1,2,3,4,5,6,..}set even integers: {2,4,6,...}Set "even
			integers" being a subset of "all integers", and if "all integers" turn pink then "even
			integers" would turn pink due to inheritance by set theory. Therefore, ger toshav is not
			a subset of goy. Rather, a ger toshav(a non-idolator) is no longer a goy(idolator). They
			are not goy(idolator). They are ger(non-idolator).The only way(and I would agree with
			you) that gerim are subsets, is in the Torah definition of goy, such as bnei Yisrael
			being a goy kodesh(a holy nation). However, we're not talking in the written Torah term,
			but rather in the halachic term, as defined by the Rambam, Hilchot Maachalot Assurot
			11:8:"when we say plainly 'goy', we mean an idolator". Hilchot Maachalot Assurot 11:8 is
			true statement. If it is true, the you should read Issurei Biah 14:7 as:"Who is a ger
			toshav? This is an idolator which accepts upon himself to not serve idolatry, [along]
			with the other commandments commanded to the children of Noach"This also explains why
			rabbis refer to ger toshav as "half-converts"(as in Avodah Berurah, Avodah Zarah 64b).
			They were once idol-worshippers, who accepted not to be.You have not shown my argument
			to be invalid or false. Standing alone and apart from the rest of Mishneh Torah, your
			argument for Issurei Biah is valid(which would assume the Torah definition of goy), but
			coupled with the axiom of Maachalot Assurot 11:8(which assumes the halachic Rambam
			definition of goy), your argument is not valid.</para>
	</sect1>
</chapter>
