<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<chapter id="ger_toshav">
	<title>Resident Sojourners</title>
	<subtitle>גרם תושבם - Gerim Toshvim </subtitle>
	<para><emphasis>Gerim toshvim</emphasis> is the plural form of <emphasis>ger toshav</emphasis>.
			<emphasis>Ger toshav</emphasis>
	</para>
	<para>2 Samuel 15:19-21<footnote>
			<para>"Then said the king to Ittai the Gittite, Wherefore goest thou also with us?
				return to thy place, and abide with the king: for thou art a stranger, and also an
				exile. Whereas thou camest but yesterday, should I this day make thee go up and down
				with us? seeing I go whither I may, return thou, and take back thy brethren: mercy
				and truth be with thee. And Ittai answered the king, and said, As the LORD liveth,
				and as my lord the king liveth, surely in what place my lord the king shall be,
				whether in death or life, even there also will thy servant be. And David said to
				Ittai, Go and pass over. And Ittai the Gittite passed over, and all his men, and all
				the little ones that were with him. And all the country wept with a loud voice, and
				all the people passed over: the king also himself passed over the brook Kidron, and
				all the people passed over, toward the way of the wilderness." - 2 Samuel 15:19-23
				KJV</para>
		</footnote> is talking about the acceptance process of the <emphasis>nochri</emphasis> to a
			<emphasis>ger toshav</emphasis>.</para>
	<sidebar>
		<para><emphasis role="bold"><emphasis>mekablin</emphasis> of the <emphasis>ger
				toshav</emphasis></emphasis>: <emphasis>Mekablin</emphasis> means
				<emphasis>acceptance</emphasis>. When someone accepts you into their fraternity,
			into their city walls, or into their country as a citizen, they
				<emphasis>mekablin</emphasis> you. You perform an oath to a constitution or some
			creed so that you and the other party are on the same understanding and expectation. The
			word <emphasis>mekablin</emphasis> creates a high amount of confusion when it relates to
			non-Jews and <emphasis>ger toshav</emphasis> in particular. Many, Rabbis included, will
			say the <emphasis>ger toshav</emphasis> does not exist today. However, that is not true.
			What the <emphasis>R"AMBAM</emphasis> says is that the <emphasis>ger toshav</emphasis>
			is not <emphasis>mekablin</emphasis> today; not that he doesn't exist. The
				<emphasis>R"AAVAD</emphasis> on <emphasis>Hilchot Issurei Bi'ah 14:7-8</emphasis>
			explains that the <emphasis>ger toshav</emphasis> most certainly does exist today. He is
			just not <emphasis>mekablin</emphasis> because the <emphasis>Yovel</emphasis> year is
			not in practice.</para>
	</sidebar>
	<sect1>
		<title>History</title>
		<para>This History of the <emphasis>ger toshav</emphasis>. The Latin
				<emphasis>proselyte</emphasis> literally means <emphasis>resident
				sojourner</emphasis></para>
	</sect1>
	<sect1>
		<title>Halacha</title>
		<para>Halachah for the <emphasis>ger toshav</emphasis></para>
	</sect1>
	<sect1>
		<title>Responsa</title>
		<para><emphasis role="bold">Statement:</emphasis> The Ger Toshav doesn't exist today</para>
		<para><emphasis role="bold">Response:</emphasis> Raavad on Hilchot Issurei Bi'ah 14:7-8</para>
		<para><emphasis role="bold">Statement:</emphasis> A <emphasis>ger toshav</emphasis> is still
			a <emphasis>goy</emphasis></para>
		<para><emphasis role="bold">Response:</emphasis> Hilchot Maachalot Assurot 11:8:"when we say
			plainly 'goy', we mean an idolator".</para>
		<para>Concerning the Issurei Biah 14:7:You say that the ger toshav is a goy even after he
			swears off idolatry.Using that logic, when Issurei Biah 13:3 says a ger tzedek is a goy
			as well, you're still able to call him a goy:"When a goy desires to enter into the
			covenant..."However, a ger tzedek is no longer a goy, lest you say all converts cannot
			keep shabbat, study Torah, etc. per Hilchot Melachim 10:9 "A goy cannot study Torah...".
			Following the rule in set theory, a subset follows all the attributes of its superset,
			so when you call a ger a subset of goy, this cannot be the case.</para>
		<para>For instance:set all integers: {1,2,3,4,5,6,..}set even integers: {2,4,6,...}Set "even
			integers" being a subset of "all integers", and if "all integers" turn pink then "even
			integers" would turn pink due to inheritance by set theory. Therefore, ger toshav is not
			a subset of goy. Rather, a ger toshav(a non-idolator) is no longer a goy(idolator). They
			are not goy(idolator). They are ger(non-idolator).The only way(and I would agree with
			you) that gerim are subsets, is in the Torah definition of goy, such as bnei Yisrael
			being a goy kodesh(a holy nation). However, we're not talking in the written Torah term,
			but rather in the halachic term, as defined by the Rambam, Hilchot Maachalot Assurot
			11:8:"when we say plainly 'goy', we mean an idolator". Hilchot Maachalot Assurot 11:8 is
			true statement. If it is true, the you should read Issurei Biah 14:7 as:"Who is a ger
			toshav? This is an idolator which accepts upon himself to not serve idolatry, [along]
			with the other commandments commanded to the children of Noach"This also explains why
			rabbis refer to ger toshav as "half-converts"(as in Avodah Berurah, Avodah Zarah 64b).
			They were once idol-worshippers, who accepted not to be.You have not shown my argument
			to be invalid or false. Standing alone and apart from the rest of Mishneh Torah, your
			argument for Issurei Biah is valid(which would assume the Torah definition of goy), but
			coupled with the axiom of Maachalot Assurot 11:8(which assumes the halachic Rambam
			definition of goy), your argument is not valid.</para>
	</sect1>
</chapter>
