<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
	<chapter id="ger_tzedek">
	<title>Sojourners of Righteousness</title>
	<subtitle>גרי צדק - Gerei Tzedek</subtitle>
	<para>This is probably the hardest of the <emphasis>gerim</emphasis> to translate. The reason is
		that the Hebrew word <emphasis>tzedek</emphasis> doesn't have a word to translate to that
		encompasses its properties of truth, correctness, uprightness, and righteousness.</para>
	<para><emphasis>Sojourners of Righteousness</emphasis> are seekers of Torah in whatever form they
		find it. They strive to constantly know <emphasis>haShem</emphasis> better and clearer. They
		are always increasing and never decreasing in this pursuit. If they fail, they spiritually
		fall to the status of <emphasis>ger toshav</emphasis>: the ger that is resting in
		place.</para>
	<sidebar>
		<para><emphasis role="bold">Note:</emphasis>
			<emphasis>Gerei Tzedek</emphasis> is often translated as <emphasis>converts</emphasis>,
				<emphasis>proselytes</emphasis>, or <emphasis>righteous strangers</emphasis>.
			Actually, <emphasis>gerei tzedek</emphasis> is a Hebrew construct and should be
			translated as <emphasis>sojourners <emphasis role="bold">of</emphasis>
				righteousness</emphasis>. It is hard ot translate <emphasis>tzedek</emphasis> into
			English and "righteousness" is probably the closest thing. In my opinion, a more proper
			definition of <emphasis>tzedek</emphasis> would be something like "proper path" or
			"proper way".</para>
		<para>This, more proper translation, lends <emphasis>gerei tzedek</emphasis> to be sojourner
			who are in a process of walking a proper path and not necessarily at the goal of the
			path. Such a <emphasis>ger</emphasis> is a <emphasis>ger gamor</emphasis>, or
				<emphasis>complete ger</emphasis>. It appears to me, that this is an individual that
			comes before a <emphasis>beit din</emphasis> to be accepted as a <emphasis>ger
				tzedek</emphasis> proper.</para>
	</sidebar>
	<para>We can deduce that a <emphasis>ger tzedek</emphasis> exists outside of acceptance ot a
			<emphasis>beit din</emphasis> because someone who does <emphasis>teshuvah</emphasis> is
		a <emphasis>tzaddik</emphasis> at that moment. Also, any <emphasis>ger</emphasis> who is
		truly seeking haShem, Torah, or attaching to his people for the sake of Heaven is a
			<emphasis>ger tzedek</emphasis>. This type <emphasis>ger tzedek</emphasis> is one
		inwardly and is subjective. There is another <emphasis>ger tzedek</emphasis>, a
			<emphasis>ger gamor</emphasis> or completed ger, that objectively goes before a
			<emphasis>beit din</emphasis> to be tried and accepted as a <emphasis>ger
			tzedek</emphasis>.</para>
	<para>Going before a <emphasis>beit din</emphasis> and asking to be accepted as a <emphasis>ger
			tzedek</emphasis> is required by halacha to become part of <emphasis>klal
			Yisrael</emphasis>. Before this acceptance by a <emphasis>beit din</emphasis>, the
			<emphasis>ger tzedek</emphasis> cannot and should not expect others to accept him as a
			<emphasis>ger tzedek</emphasis>, particularly in a Jewish community. Some reasons for
		this, is because <emphasis>klal Yisrael</emphasis> has certain halachic obligations to the
			<emphasis>ger</emphasis> and at this time when there is no <emphasis>Yovel</emphasis>
		year, only the <emphasis>ger tzedek</emphasis> can be accepted and have those obligations
		met. It is a <emphasis>mizvah</emphasis> for <emphasis>klal Yisrael</emphasis> to love the
			<emphasis>ger</emphasis> and not taunt him. The <emphasis>ger</emphasis> should also
		love <emphasis>bnei Yisrael</emphasis> and not expect them to open their gates of the
		community to just anyone who comes off the street. That would be dangerous and
		unloving.</para>
	<sect1>
		<title>History</title>
		<para>This History of the <emphasis>ger tzedek</emphasis></para>
	</sect1>
	<sect1>
		<title>Halacha</title>
		<para>Halachah for the <emphasis>ger tzedek</emphasis></para>
	</sect1>
	<sect1>
		<title>Responsa</title>
		<para>The <emphasis>ger tzedek </emphasis>doesn't exist today</para>
	</sect1>
</chapter>
