<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
	<chapter id="ger_tzedek">
	<title>Sojourners of Righteousness</title>
	<subtitle>גרי צדק - Gerei Tzedek</subtitle>
	<para>This is probably the hardest of the <emphasis>gerim</emphasis> to translate. The reason is
		that the Hebrew word <emphasis>tzedek</emphasis> doesn't have a word to translate to that
		encompasses its properties of truth, correctness, uprightness, and righteousness.</para>
	<para><emphasis>Sojourners of Righteousness</emphasis> are seekers of Torah in whatever form they
		find it. They strive to constantly know <emphasis>haShem</emphasis> better and clearer. They
		are always increasing and never decreasing in this pursuit. If they fail, they spiritually
		fall to the status of <emphasis>ger toshav</emphasis>: the ger that is resting in
		place.</para>
	<para>The <emphasis>ger tzedek</emphasis> is the ultimate path that <emphasis>haShem</emphasis>
		desires for the <emphasis>goy</emphasis>. The <emphasis>ger tzedek</emphasis> was from the
		lowly source of a <emphasis>goy</emphasis>, but is now seeking the ultimate Source of his
		true existence: <emphasis>haShem</emphasis>. However, <emphasis>haShem</emphasis> does not
		require a <emphasis>goy</emphasis> to become a <emphasis>ger tzedek</emphasis>.
			<emphasis>haShem</emphasis> only requires that he keep the <emphasis>sheva mitzvot bnei
			Noach</emphasis>. The passive nature of the <emphasis>sheva mitzvot bnei
			Noach</emphasis> allows the <emphasis>goy</emphasis>(if he keeps the <emphasis>sheva
			mitzvot bnei Noach</emphasis> he is now a plain <emphasis>ben Noach</emphasis>) to do as
		he pleases so long as he does not transgress the seven. It appears to me that these are
		designed in such a way to restrict any damage to creation if the <emphasis>ben
			Noach</emphasis> does not desire to seek his Source: <emphasis>haShem</emphasis>.
		However, the stringincy of the laws most likely will incentivise the <emphasis>ben
			Noach</emphasis> to seek the Source of the harsh judgements of the seven, should he
		transgress them. The initiation by <emphasis>haShem Elokim</emphasis> to give the harsh laws
		for <emphasis>bnei Noach</emphasis> is so that <emphasis>bnei Noach</emphasis> will be
		encouraged to seek the Source of the harsh judgements. This initiation by <emphasis>haShem
			Elokim</emphasis> is given through the teaching of His <emphasis>Torah</emphasis>, by
		the elders of his community, etc. This is called illah eltatah(the higher initiation). "Why
		does <emphasis>Elokim</emphasis> act so harshly toward me if I trangress? If I even steal a
			<emphasis>pruta's</emphasis> worth of someone else's, I am worthy of decapitation!" When
		the <emphasis>ben Noach</emphasis> starts to earnestly question why these judgements are so
		harsh and starts to seek their Source, the judgements are now sweatened, because he is now
		seeking the Wisdom of <emphasis>haShem</emphasis>. This is called illah teta'ah(the lower
		initiation). This is the beginning of the path of the <emphasis>ger tzedek</emphasis>. The
		fear of <emphasis>haShem</emphasis> is the beginning of Wisdom. This wisdom leads to the
			<emphasis>da'at</emphasis>. <emphasis>Da'at</emphasis> leads to a love of
			<emphasis>haShem</emphasis>. The love of <emphasis>haShem</emphasis> leads to doing
		positive commandments. The purpose of Wisdom is teshuvah and good deeds.<footnote>
			<para> Brachos 17a</para>
		</footnote></para>
	<para>The <emphasis>ger tzedek</emphasis> may spiritually occilate out of this seeking and
		yearning and fall to a lesser status such as a <emphasis>ger toshav</emphasis> or
			<emphasis>goy</emphasis>.</para>
	<sidebar>
		<para><emphasis role="bold">Note:</emphasis>
			<emphasis>Gerei Tzedek</emphasis> is often translated as <emphasis>converts</emphasis>,
				<emphasis>proselytes</emphasis>, or <emphasis>righteous strangers</emphasis>.
			Actually, <emphasis>gerei tzedek</emphasis> is a Hebrew construct and should be
			translated as <emphasis>sojourners <emphasis role="bold">of</emphasis>
				righteousness</emphasis>. It is hard to translate <emphasis>tzedek</emphasis> into
			English and "righteousness" is probably the closest thing. In my opinion, a more proper
			definition of <emphasis>tzedek</emphasis> would be something like "proper path" or
			"proper way".</para>
		<para>This, more proper translation, lends <emphasis>gerei tzedek</emphasis> to be sojourners who
			are in a process of walking a proper path and not necessarily already at the destination
			of the path. Such a <emphasis>ger</emphasis> is a <emphasis>ger gamor</emphasis>, or
				<emphasis>complete ger</emphasis> and one who begins to settle.
				<emphasis>Gerim</emphasis> are known to live in tents and not permanent dwellings.
			It appears to me, that such a person is an individual that comes before a <emphasis>beit
				din</emphasis> to be accepted as a <emphasis>ger tzedek</emphasis> proper.</para>
	</sidebar>
	<para>We can deduce that a <emphasis>ger tzedek</emphasis> exists outside of acceptance ot a
			<emphasis>beit din</emphasis> because someone who does <emphasis>teshuvah</emphasis> is
		a <emphasis>tzaddik</emphasis> at that moment. Also, any <emphasis>ger</emphasis> who is
		truly seeking haShem, Torah, or attaching to his people for the sake of Heaven is a
			<emphasis>ger tzedek</emphasis>. This type <emphasis>ger tzedek</emphasis> is one
		inwardly and is subjective. There is another <emphasis>ger tzedek</emphasis>, a
			<emphasis>ger gamor</emphasis> or completed ger, that objectively goes before a
			<emphasis>beit din</emphasis> to be tried and accepted as a <emphasis>ger
			tzedek</emphasis>.</para>
	<para>Going before a <emphasis>beit din</emphasis> and asking to be accepted as a <emphasis>ger
			tzedek</emphasis> is required by halacha to become part of <emphasis>klal
			Yisrael</emphasis>. Before this acceptance by a <emphasis>beit din</emphasis>, the
			<emphasis>ger tzedek</emphasis> cannot and should not expect others to accept him as a
			<emphasis>ger tzedek</emphasis>, particularly in a Jewish community. Some reasons for
		this, is because <emphasis>klal Yisrael</emphasis> has certain halachic obligations to the
			<emphasis>ger</emphasis> and at this time when there is no practicing
			<emphasis>Yovel</emphasis>, only the <emphasis>ger tzedek</emphasis> can be accepted and
		have those obligations met. It is a <emphasis>mitzvah</emphasis> for <emphasis>klal
			Yisrael</emphasis> to love the <emphasis>ger</emphasis> and not taunt him. The
			<emphasis>ger</emphasis> should also love <emphasis>bnei Yisrael</emphasis> and not
		expect them to open their gates of the community to just anyone who comes off the street.
		That would be dangerous and unloving. Therefore, one should not refer to themselves as a
			<emphasis>ger tzedek</emphasis> unless confirmed as such.</para>
	<para>"Every year a Jew must reach a level of renewal and "geirus" similar to that of a newborn
		baby. This is the whole idea behind the seven weeks of counting the omer, a time for
		purifying oneself of impurities in order to reach a level of "geirus"." - Nesivos Sholom,
		Shavuos - Ma'amar Echad, B'Yom haBikkurim B'Hikrivchem Mincha Chadasha L'haShem, sup Bnei
		Avraham Ahuvecha: Gerim in Chassidic Thought. A ger( tzedek or toshav) is like a newborn
		baby: read Avodah Berurah, Avodah Zara 64b. The ger and the ben Yisrael has the same
		spiritual state. Both animal souls are emanating from klipat nogah and refining until a
		Godly soul is welcomed, which is Shavuot.</para>
	<sect1>
		<title>History</title>
		<para>This History of the <emphasis>ger tzedek</emphasis></para>
	</sect1>
	<sect1>
		<title>Halacha</title>
		<para>Halachah for the <emphasis>ger tzedek</emphasis>. Hilchot Issurei Bi'ah 13:4</para>
	</sect1>
	<sect1>
		<title>Responsa</title>
		<para><emphasis role="bold">Statement:</emphasis> The <emphasis>ger tzedek</emphasis> must be
			mekablin</para>
		<para><emphasis role="bold">Response:</emphasis> The <emphasis>ger tzedek</emphasis> exists
			even outside of <emphasis>mekablin</emphasis> to a <emphasis>beit din</emphasis>. It's
			just that the <emphasis>ger tzedek</emphasis> is not revealed that he is a <emphasis>ger
				tzedek</emphasis> until he is <emphasis>mekablin</emphasis>. He cannot go around
			telling <emphasis>klal Yisrael</emphasis> that he is a <emphasis>ger tzedek</emphasis>
			and expect <emphasis>klal Yisrael</emphasis> to interact with him as such until he is
				<emphasis>mekablin</emphasis> by a <emphasis>beit din</emphasis>.</para>
	</sect1>
</chapter>
