<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<chapter id="intro">
    <title>Introduction</title>
    <para>This book is out to rectify injustices done from impure speech; particularly in the usage
        of the categories of non-Jews within Jewish Law: the <emphasis>Torah</emphasis>. This book
        will help to end anti-semitism by rehumanizing the non-Jew within the
            <emphasis>Torah</emphasis> through the lens of proper terms used for non-Jews and their
        respective laws. There is a vicious cycle of dehumanization between the Jew and non-Jew that
        can be stopped by using pure speech and logical application of that speech to proper
        definitions within <emphasis>Torah</emphasis>. Specifically, this book is about subsets of
        non-Jews, their critical definitions, and <emphasis>Torah</emphasis> law pertaining to their
        respective non-Jew subsets. These subsets are either entirely mutually exclusive, or have
        only some mutual exclusivity in respect to their properties. For instance, the set of all
        humans have chromosomes, but not all humans keep kosher; so the subsets are defined in
        respect to the properties talked about. This book is about specific subsets and their
        respective properties. These subsets or categories, are called <emphasis>gedarim</emphasis>
        in Hebrew.</para>
    <para>Once the reader sees the different <emphasis>gedarim</emphasis> of non-Jews within
            <emphasis>Torah</emphasis> using their proper Hebrew nouns as described in this book,
        the reader will be able to see the improper usage of terms about the different non-Jews and
        how such terms lead to misunderstanding and misapplication of <emphasis>Torah</emphasis>
        law, foundational misquotes for antisemitism, etc. An example, is a translation of a major
        redactor of Jewish Law known as the R"AMBAM which says in his <emphasis>Mishneh
            Torah</emphasis> that a non-Jew who studies the Torah is obligated to die. Such a
        translation that depicts all non-Jews not only sounds horrible, it's wrong. In reality, the
        verse in the original Hebrew is only in relation to <emphasis role="bold">wicked</emphasis>
        non-Jews, who for the most part in our western culture today, don't exist. Unfortunately,
        this is the common translation of such verses of <emphasis>Torah</emphasis> law pertaining
        to non-Jews. Such translations promulgate within the Jewish community and eventually end up
        in the non-Jewish community.</para>
    <para><emphasis>Gedarim</emphasis> have certain properties associated with them. For instance,
        let's look at the word <emphasis>goy</emphasis>. The <emphasis>geder</emphasis> for
            <emphasis>goy</emphasis> has a legal status such that a <emphasis>goy</emphasis> that
        gives <emphasis>tzedakah</emphasis>/charity to <emphasis>bnei Yisrael</emphasis>:
            <emphasis>bnei Yisrael</emphasis> cannot benefit from that <emphasis>tzedakah</emphasis>
        and the <emphasis>tzedakah</emphasis> must be given instead to the <emphasis>goy</emphasis>
        poor. However, when a <emphasis>ben Noach</emphasis>/child of Noah, which is under a
        different <emphasis>geder</emphasis> gives charity to <emphasis>bnei Yisrael</emphasis>, the
        poor of <emphasis>bnei Yisrael</emphasis> can use that <emphasis>tzedakah</emphasis>. Even
        more so, <emphasis>Yisrael</emphasis> has a <emphasis>mitzvah</emphasis> to sustain the life
        of a <emphasis>ben Noach</emphasis>, while <emphasis>bnei Yisrael</emphasis> have no
            <emphasis>mitzvah</emphasis> for the <emphasis>goy</emphasis>. Even contrary,
            <emphasis>bnei Yisrael</emphasis> are obligated to not save a <emphasis>goy</emphasis>
        from death. What is a <emphasis>goy</emphasis>? What is a <emphasis>ben Noach</emphasis>?
        Why are they treated differently? Many will tell you that the <emphasis>goy</emphasis> and
        the <emphasis>ben Noach</emphasis> are the same thing: that they're all
            <emphasis>gentiles</emphasis> or non-Jews. However, they're not. These different
        categories of non-Jews will be explained in this book. This book will properly show some
        correct definitions and differences of these <emphasis>gedarim</emphasis> of non-Jews, which
        will expose many horrible translations or misunderstandings about quotes of
            <emphasis>Torah</emphasis> taken out of context to wrongfully justify de-humanization or
        hatred of the Jew and non-Jew. The R"AMBAM in his Mishneh Torah, Hilchot Melachim 10:10,
        shows a good example of two different <emphasis>gedarim</emphasis>.<footnote>
            <para>"A <emphasis>ben Noach</emphasis> that wants to do a
                <emphasis>mitzvah</emphasis>/commandment from the other <emphasis>mitzvot</emphasis>
                of the <emphasis>Torah</emphasis>(beyond the seven of <emphasis>bnei
                    Noach</emphasis>) in order to receive reward, [<emphasis>Yisrael</emphasis>]
                does not keep him from doing it properly. And if he brings a burnt offering, we
                receive it. If he gives <emphasis>tzedakah</emphasis>, we receive it from him and it
                appears to me that it is given to the poor of <emphasis>Yisrael</emphasis>. He
                receives his sustenance from <emphasis>Yisrael</emphasis> and it is a
                    <emphasis>mitzvah</emphasis> to sustain his life. However, the
                    <emphasis>goy</emphasis> that gives <emphasis>tzedakah</emphasis>, we receive it
                and give it to the poor <emphasis>goyim</emphasis>" - R"AMBAM, Hilchot Melachim
                10:10</para>
        </footnote> Even though both <emphasis>goy</emphasis> and <emphasis>ben Noach</emphasis> are
        in the set of non-Jews, they are their own respective subset with their own respective
        properties and laws. These sets or categories are called <emphasis>gedarim</emphasis> and it
        is these sets and their respective properties is mostly what this book is about.</para>
</chapter>
