<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<chapter id="intro">
    <title>Introduction</title>
    <para>This book is out to rectify injustices done from impure speech; particularly in the usage
        of the categories of non-Jews within Jewish Law: the <emphasis>Torah</emphasis>. This book
        will help to re-humanize the non-Jew within the <emphasis>Torah</emphasis> by clarifying
        proper terms used for non-Jews and their respective laws that unfortunately get convoluted
        and overlooked. There is a vicious cycle of de-humanization between the Jew and non-Jew that
        can be stopped by using pure speech and logical application of that speech to proper
        definitions within <emphasis>Torah</emphasis>. <emphasis>Torah</emphasis> has never been the
        problem. Rather, misunderstandings of different types of non-Jews is the main problem in
        this regard. Many today don't even realize there are different types of non-Jews in
            <emphasis>Torah</emphasis>, each with their own treatment. Specifically, this book is
        about subsets of non-Jews, their critical definitions, and <emphasis>Torah</emphasis> law
        pertaining to their respective non-Jew subsets. These subsets are either entirely mutually
        exclusive, or have only some exclusivity in respect to their properties. For instance, all
        humans have chromosomes, but not all humans keep kosher; so the subsets are defined in
        respect to the properties wrote about in this book. This book is about specific subsets of
        non-Jews and their respective properties. These subsets or categories, are called
            <emphasis>gedarim</emphasis> in Hebrew.</para>
    <para>Once the reader sees the different <emphasis>gedarim</emphasis> of non-Jews within
            <emphasis>Torah</emphasis> using their proper Hebrew nouns as described in this book,
        the reader will be able to see the improper usage of terms about the different non-Jews and
        how such terms lead to misunderstanding and misapplication of <emphasis>Torah</emphasis>
        law, foundational misquotes used for antisemitism, etc. An example, is a translation of a
        major redactor of Jewish Law known as the R"AMBAM which says in his <emphasis>Mishneh
            Torah</emphasis> that a non-Jew who studies the Torah is obligated to die.<footnote
            id="h_melachim_9_9">
            <para>R"AMBAM, Mishneh Torah, Hilchot Melachim 10:9</para>
        </footnote> Such a translation that depicts all non-Jews not only sounds horrible, it's
        actually wrong. In reality, the verse in the original Hebrew is describing <emphasis
            role="bold">wicked</emphasis> non-Jews, who for the most part in our western culture
        today, don't exist. Unfortunately, the aforementioned translation is the common translation
        of such verses of <emphasis>Torah</emphasis> law pertaining to non-Jews. Such translations
        and traditions about the non-Jew promulgate within the unlearned Jewish community and
        eventually end up in the non-Jewish community where the damage comes full circle.
        Thankfully, with proper understanding, this grave misunderstanding can be remedied. With
        this book, I hope to bring to light this proper understanding and will help usher in the
        true view of Torah being a pleasant and peaceful path.<footnote><para>"Her ways are pleasant ways, and all her paths are peace." - Proverbs 3:17</para></footnote></para>
    <para><emphasis>Gedarim</emphasis> have certain properties associated with them. For instance,
        let's look at the word <emphasis>goy</emphasis>. The <emphasis>geder</emphasis> for
            <emphasis>goy</emphasis> has a legal status such that a <emphasis>goy</emphasis> that
        gives <emphasis>tzedakah</emphasis>/charity to <emphasis>bnei Yisrael</emphasis>/child of
        Israel(colloquially: a Jew): <emphasis>bnei Yisrael</emphasis>
        <emphasis role="bold">cannot</emphasis> benefit from that <emphasis>tzedakah</emphasis> and
        the <emphasis>tzedakah</emphasis> must be given instead to the <emphasis>goy</emphasis>
        poor. However, when a <emphasis>ben Noach</emphasis>/child of Noah, which is under a
        different <emphasis>geder</emphasis> gives charity to <emphasis>bnei Yisrael</emphasis>, the
        poor of <emphasis>bnei Yisrael</emphasis>
        <emphasis role="bold">can</emphasis> use that <emphasis>tzedakah</emphasis>. Even more so,
            <emphasis>Yisrael</emphasis> has a <emphasis>mitzvah</emphasis>/commandment to sustain
        the life of a <emphasis>ben Noach</emphasis> in trouble, while <emphasis>bnei
            Yisrael</emphasis> have no such <emphasis>mitzvah</emphasis> for the
            <emphasis>goy</emphasis>. Even contrary, <emphasis>bnei Yisrael</emphasis> are obligated
        to not save a <emphasis>goy</emphasis> from death. So then, one must ask: What is a
            <emphasis>goy</emphasis>? What is a <emphasis>ben Noach</emphasis>? Why are they treated
        differently?</para>
    <para>These different categories of non-Jews will be explained in this book. This book will
        properly show some correct definitions and differences of these <emphasis>gedarim</emphasis>
        of non-Jews, which will expose many horrible translations or misunderstandings about quotes
        of <emphasis>Torah</emphasis>. This book will help break the vicious cycle of ignorance by
        bringing back purity of language, which will help bring pleasantness and peace.<footnote>
            <para>"For then I will restore to the peoples a pure language, That they all may call on
                    <emphasis>haShem</emphasis>, To serve Him with one accord." - Zephaniah
                3:9</para>
        </footnote> The R"AMBAM in his Mishneh Torah, Hilchot Melachim 10:10, shows a good example
        of two different <emphasis>gedarim</emphasis>.<footnote id="h_melachim_10_10">
            <para>"A <emphasis>ben Noach</emphasis> that wants to do a
                <emphasis>mitzvah</emphasis>/commandment from the other <emphasis>mitzvot</emphasis>
                of the <emphasis>Torah</emphasis>(beyond the seven of <emphasis>bnei
                    Noach</emphasis>) in order to receive reward, [<emphasis>Yisrael</emphasis>]
                does not keep him from doing it properly. And if he brings a burnt offering, we
                receive it. If he gives <emphasis>tzedakah</emphasis>, we receive it from him and it
                appears to me that it is given to the poor of <emphasis>Yisrael</emphasis>. He
                receives his sustenance from <emphasis>Yisrael</emphasis> and it is a
                    <emphasis>mitzvah</emphasis> to sustain his life. However, the
                    <emphasis>goy</emphasis> that gives <emphasis>tzedakah</emphasis>, we receive it
                and give it to the poor <emphasis>goyim</emphasis>" - R"AMBAM, Mishneh Torah,
                Hilchot Melachim 10:10</para>
        </footnote>Many will tell you that the <emphasis>goy</emphasis> and the <emphasis>ben
            Noach</emphasis> are the same thing: that they're all the <emphasis>gentile</emphasis>
        or the non-Jew in <emphasis>Torah</emphasis> and this is often how <emphasis>goy</emphasis>
        and <emphasis>gentile</emphasis> are translated from the Hebrew. However, as one can see,
        they are <emphasis role="bold">not</emphasis> the same. There is some mutual exclusivity, as
        we just read, between the <emphasis>goy</emphasis> and the <emphasis>ben Noach</emphasis>
        who gives <emphasis>tzedakah</emphasis>. Even though both <emphasis>goy</emphasis> and
            <emphasis>ben Noach</emphasis> are in the set of non-Jews, they are their own respective
        subset with their own respective properties and <emphasis>dinim</emphasis>/laws. These sets
        or categories are called <emphasis>gedarim</emphasis> and it is these sets and their
        respective properties which is what this book is about. </para>
</chapter>
