<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<chapter id="intro">
    <title>Introduction</title>
    <para>This book is about specific sub-sets of non-Jews. These subsets are either entirely
        mutually exclusive, or have only some mutual exclusivity in respect to their properties. For
        instance, all humans have chromosomes, but not all humans keep kosher; so the subsets are
        defined in respect to the properties talked about. This book is about specific subsets and
        their respective properties. These subsets or categories, are called
            <emphasis>gedarim</emphasis> in Hebrew.</para>
    <para><emphasis>Gedarim</emphasis> have certain properties associated with them. For instance,
        let's take a look at the word <emphasis>goy</emphasis>. The <emphasis>geder</emphasis> for
            <emphasis>goy</emphasis> is such that a <emphasis>goy</emphasis> that gives
            <emphasis>tzedakah</emphasis>/charity to <emphasis>bnei Yisrael</emphasis>:
            <emphasis>bnei Yisrael</emphasis> cannot benefit from that <emphasis>tzedakah</emphasis>
        and the <emphasis>tzedakah</emphasis> must be given instead to the <emphasis>goy</emphasis>
        poor. However, when a <emphasis>ben Noach</emphasis>/child of Noah, which is under a
        different <emphasis>geder</emphasis> gives charity to <emphasis>bnei Yisrael</emphasis>, the
        poor of <emphasis>bnei Yisrael</emphasis> can use that <emphasis>tzedakah</emphasis>. What
        is a <emphasis>goy</emphasis>? What is a <emphasis>ben Noach</emphasis>? Why are they
        treated differently? Many will tell you that the <emphasis>goy</emphasis> and the
            <emphasis>ben Noach</emphasis> are the same thing. However, they're not. These different
        categories of non-Jews will be explained in this book. This book will properly show some
        correct definitions and differences of these <emphasis>gedarim</emphasis> of non-Jews, which
        will expose many horrible translations or misunderstandings about quotes of
            <emphasis>Torah</emphasis> taken out of context to wrongfully justify de-huminization or
        hatred of the Jew and non-Jew.<footnote>
            <para>"A <emphasis>ben Noach</emphasis> that wants to do a
                <emphasis>mitzvah</emphasis>/commandment from the other <emphasis>mitzvot</emphasis>
                of the <emphasis>Torah</emphasis>(beyond the seven of <emphasis>bnei
                    Noach</emphasis>) in order to receive reward, [<emphasis>Yisrael</emphasis>]
                does not keep him from doing it properly. And if he brings a burnt offering, we
                receive it. If he gives <emphasis>tzedakah</emphasis>, we receive it from him and it
                appears to me that it is given to the poor of <emphasis>Yisrael</emphasis>. He
                receives his sustenance from <emphasis>Yisrael</emphasis> and it is a
                    <emphasis>mitzvah</emphasis> to sustane his life. However, a
                    <emphasis>goy</emphasis> that gives <emphasis>tzedakah</emphasis>, we receive it
                and give it to the poor <emphasis>goyim</emphasis> -  R"AMBAM, Hilchot Melachim
                10:10</para>
        </footnote> This shows a good example of two different <emphasis>gedarim</emphasis> even
        though both <emphasis>goy</emphasis> and <emphasis>ben Noach</emphasis> are in the set of
        non-Jews. <emphasis>Gedarim</emphasis> and there given properties is mostly what this book
        is about.</para>
</chapter>
