<!DOCTYPE part PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<part>
    <title>People of the World</title>
    <subtitle>אומות העולם - Umot haOlam</subtitle>
    <partintro>
        <para><emphasis> Umot haOlam</emphasis> is translated as "People of the World". Within the
            set of <emphasis>Umot haOlam</emphasis> are specific subsets. Depending on what the set
            is referring to, these subsets are either subsets entirely, or have some mutual
            exclusivity, in respect to properties. For instance, all humans have chromosomes, but
            not all humans keep kosher; it's in respect to the properties talk about.</para>
        <para>Every human being takes an oath in utero to be righteous(Niddah 30b, Iyov). The
                <emphasis>Umot haOlam</emphasis> have forsaken this oath.</para>
        <para>Every human being has 248 bones that desire to do <emphasis>mitzvot</emphasis>(Rambam
            from Sefer Mitzvot). The <emphasis>Umot haOlam</emphasis> forsake this desire.</para>
        <para>Every human being who's spirit moves them, can obtain understanding and with his
            knowledge set himself different and stand before <emphasis>haShem</emphasis>, to serve
            and minister to Him and to know <emphasis>haShem</emphasis>, walking straight as
                <emphasis>Elokim</emphasis> made him, and and can remove the yoke of the thoughts of
                <emphasis>bnei Adam</emphasis>. This human being is sanctified like the
                <emphasis>Kadosh Kadoshim</emphasis>. <emphasis>haShem</emphasis> is his portion and
            heritage forever and will provide what is sufficient for him in this world like He
            provides for priests and Levites. Thus David, peace be upon him, said<footnote>
                <para>Tehillim 16:5</para>
            </footnote> "haShem is my lot and my portion; You are my cup; you support my lot." <footnote>
                <para>Rambam, Mishneh Torah, Hilchot Shemita v'Yovel 13:13</para>
            </footnote></para>
        <para>Every living thing with blood in its body has an animal soul called a <emphasis>nefesh
                behemut</emphasis>. All <emphasis>nefeshot behemut</emphasis> emanate from some type
            of <emphasis>klipah</emphasis> depending on what type of <emphasis>nefesh
                behemut</emphasis> it has. <emphasis>Umot haOlam</emphasis> have animal souls that
            emanate from three <emphasis>klipot</emphasis> that are impure called <emphasis>klipat
                tameyut</emphasis>.</para>
    </partintro>
		<xi:include href="umot_haolam/gentile.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"/>
		<xi:include href="umot_haolam/goy.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"/>
		<xi:include href="umot_haolam/bnei_noach.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"/>
</part>
