<!DOCTYPE part PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<part>
    <title>The People of the World</title>
    <subtitle>אומות העולם - Umot haOlam</subtitle>
    <partintro>
        <para><emphasis>Umot haOlam</emphasis> is translated as "The People of the World". Now that
            we have a little bit of information on the substance of souls that emenate from
                <emphasis>klipah</emphasis>, we can now talk about a certain type of soul that the
                <emphasis>Umot haOlam</emphasis> have. <emphasis>Umot haOlam</emphasis> is the
                <emphasis>ikkar</emphasis> term for anyone who is not <emphasis>bnei
                Yisrael</emphasis> and are connected only to this world and do not have a portion in
                <emphasis>Olam haBa</emphasis>/The World to Come.<footnote>
                <para>Lessons in Tanya, Chapter 1</para>
            </footnote>
            <emphasis>Umot haOlam</emphasis> are in contrast to <emphasis>Chasidei Umot
                haOlam</emphasis>. <emphasis>Chasidei Umot haOlam</emphasis> are not of
                <emphasis>bnei Yisrael</emphasis> in this domain, but <emphasis role="bold"
                >are</emphasis> connected to <emphasis>Olam haBa</emphasis>/The World to Come. Both
                <emphasis>Chasidei Umot haOlam</emphasis> and <emphasis>Bnei Yisrael</emphasis> have
                <emphasis>nefashot behemot</emphasis>/animal souls that emanate from the same place:
                <emphasis>klipat nogah</emphasis>, which is a mixture of pure and impure and such a
                <emphasis>nefesh</emphasis> can be elevated. <emphasis>Klipat Nogah</emphasis> is
            where all clean animals emanate from. A <emphasis>nefesh</emphasis>/soul from the
                <emphasis>klipat tameyut</emphasis> cannot yet be elevated; this is where all
            unclean animals emanate from and this is the soul type of <emphasis>Umot
                haOlam</emphasis>.</para>
        <para>Every human being takes an oath in utero to be righteous.<footnote>
                <para>Niddah 30b, Iyov</para>
            </footnote> The <emphasis>Umot haOlam</emphasis> have forsaken this oath. All human
            beings have 613 parts of the body.<footnote>
                <para>Tanya, Ari Kaplan Inner Space, Transforming the Inner Self, pg 38, ft
                    52</para>
            </footnote>
            <footnote>
                <para>Likutei Torah, Eikev 13b; 14a</para>
            </footnote> These 613 parts correlate to the 613 <emphasis>mitzvot</emphasis> written in
            the <emphasis>Torah</emphasis> and each have a respective conduit that connect to
                <emphasis>haShem</emphasis>. When you fulfill a <emphasis>mitzvah</emphasis>, you
            complete this conduit and Godliness flows into the world.<footnote>
                <para>Tanya, Iggeret haKodesh, 7</para>
            </footnote></para>
        <para>Of those 613 parts, 248 are bones that desire to do the positive
                <emphasis>mitzvot</emphasis>. All men are called to love
            <emphasis>haShem</emphasis>, whether they do so or not is up to them.<footnote>
                <para>Rambam, Book of Mitzvot, 3rd Principle(p.17 Touger)</para>
            </footnote></para>
        <para>The <emphasis>Umot haOlam</emphasis> forsake the desire to love
                <emphasis>haShem</emphasis> and are motivated only for self-serving motives. Even if
            someone from the <emphasis>Umot haOlam</emphasis> do an act of kindness, it is only to
            fulfill a selfish desire to do kindness and is not true kindness.</para>
        <sidebar><para>R"AMBAM writes: Every human being who's spirit moves them, can obtain understanding, and with
                his knowledge, set himself different and stand before <emphasis>haShem</emphasis>,
                to serve and minister to Him and to know <emphasis>haShem</emphasis>, walking
                straight as <emphasis>Elokim</emphasis> made him, and can remove the yoke of the
                thoughts of <emphasis>bnei Adam</emphasis>. This human being is sanctified like the
                    <emphasis>Kadosh Kadoshim</emphasis>. <emphasis>haShem</emphasis> is his portion
                and heritage forever and will provide what is sufficient for him in this world like
                He provides for priests and Levites. Thus David, peace be upon him, said
                    "<emphasis>haShem</emphasis> is my lot and my portion; You are my cup; you
                support my lot."<footnote>
                    <para>Tehillim 16:5</para>
                </footnote>
                <footnote>
                    <para>Rambam, Mishneh Torah, Hilchot Shemita v'Yovel 13:13</para>
                </footnote></para></sidebar>
        </partintro>
		<xi:include href="umot_haolam/gentile.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"/>
		<xi:include href="umot_haolam/goy.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"/>
		<xi:include href="umot_haolam/bnei_noach.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"/>
</part>
