<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<chapter id="gerim_gerurim">
	<title>Calculating Converts</title>
	<subtitle>גרים גרורים - Gerim Gerurim</subtitle>
	<para>Element of selfish gain for only their animal soul. As opposed to an element of fear of
		losing the life of one's animal soul like <emphasis>gerim ariyot</emphasis> from a previous
		chapter.</para>
	<para><emphasis>Gerim of Mordecai and Esther</emphasis> are most likely <emphasis>Gerim
			Gerurim</emphasis>.</para>
	<para>The etymology of the word from the etymological dictionary - gerar means to chew cud. A pig
		doesn't gerar. See conversation with Jake Fry.</para>
	<para><emphasis>Gerim Gerurim</emphasis> come for selfish motives and attach to
			<emphasis>Yisrael</emphasis> when the hand of <emphasis>Yisrael</emphasis> is strong.
		This is explained in <emphasis>Avodah Zarah</emphasis> 2b which is before the war of
			<emphasis>Gog u'Magog</emphasis>. During the war, these <emphasis>gerim
			gerurim</emphasis> will break the <emphasis>mitzvot</emphasis> they were keeping and
		cast them away. There will be a remnant of these gerim, however, that will still keep the
			<emphasis>mitzvot</emphasis> and <emphasis>haShem</emphasis> will make them and their
		language pure and all will call upon the name of haShem and serve him in oneness. This is
		explained in <emphasis>Berakhot</emphasis> 57a and the commentary on
			<emphasis>Zephaniah</emphasis> 3:9 by <emphasis>RADAK</emphasis> which shows the
			<emphasis>goyim</emphasis> returning to <emphasis>haShem</emphasis> and becoming
			<emphasis>gerim</emphasis>.<footnote>
			<para>The people who will remain after the war of Gog in their first language will make
				it clear to them that they will not utter another God in their language, but all
				will call in the name of the Lord. This is a clear language as he said in the
				prophecy of Zechariah on that day there will be one God and His name is one. Will
				turn into worshiping God alone in a clear language is the language of holiness in
				which alone is called the honorable name - <emphasis>RADAK</emphasis> on
					<emphasis>Zephaniah</emphasis> 3:9</para>
			<para>פי' העמים שישארו אחר מלחמת גוג שפתם הראשונה אהפוך אותה עליהם בשפה ברורה שלא יוציאו
				בשפתם אלהים אחרים אלא כולם יקראו בשם ה' זהו שפה ברורה כמו שאמר בנבואת זכריה ביום
				ההוא יהיה ה' אחד ושמו אחד, והחכם רבי אברהם אבן עזרא ז"ל פירש יתהפכו לעבוד ה' לבדו
				בשפה ברורה היא לשון הקדש שבה לבדה נקרא השם הנכבד:</para>
		</footnote></para>
</chapter>
