<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<chapter id="pious_people">
	<title>The Pious of the People of the World</title>
	<para><emphasis>Chassidei Umot haOlam</emphasis> is translated as "the pious of the people of the
		world". <emphasis>Chassidei Umot haOlam</emphasis> are not attached to <emphasis>bnei
			Yisrael</emphasis> like <emphasis>gerim</emphasis>. They are still attached to their
		host nation and are held hostage in a way(see Rebbe's Sichot on this matter). They would of
		been with <emphasis>klal Yisrael</emphasis> during <emphasis>maten Torah</emphasis> but
		their host nations held them hostage. Spiritually, they are attached to <emphasis>klal
			Yisrael</emphasis>, but not physically and do not gain those blessings. Those who are
		physically attached by living among <emphasis>bnei Yisrael</emphasis> are referred to as
			<emphasis>ger toshav</emphasis>. Their host nations receive blessings from them, as they
		are Chassidim; the Rebbe states this in a work gone over by Rabbi Katz, how shefah comes
		through Chassidim.</para>
	<para>You've heard it said by many Chabad Rabbis, etc. that "Chasidei Umot haOlam" is the
		greatest height a non-Jew can obtain: "unlock your true potential!", some say. However,
		"Chasidei Umot haOlam" are defined in Chabad Chassidus as people that receive a portion in
		the world to come, but do not unify haShem and do not truly yet fully believe in His Oneness
		- they believe in God, but not yet fully in his Oneness(see Siddur Im Dach, Shaar haMatzot)
		- they are still servants of the stars and constellations - avodah kochavim u'mazalot -
		A"KUM. Even if a non-Jew doesn't bow to an idol, as long as he believes "haShem is over
		there and I'm over here", then they have not rejected this shituf. They are also still apart
		of the people of the world - umot haOlam. Many Rabbis unfortunately get to this conclusion
		by misreading Hilchot Melachim 8:10-11 and have never gone further in their studies.</para>
	<para>Examples of Chasidei Umot haOlam are people that have an element of self-sacrifice for the
		common good of humanity - this is an attribute of souls that emanate from klipat nogah -
		it's a mixture of pure and impure. They believe in a higher being, even though they might
		not properly worship and still be involved in avodah zarah. Catholic priests that risked
		their lives to save Jewish children during the holocaust, Doctors, nurses, who took personal
		risks, to do similar tasks, regardless of their religious affiliation, would be considered
		Chasidei Umot haOlam. They mix the pure, which is their bitul(self-sacrifice), with the
		impure(their connection with the avodah zara of their people/nation).</para>
	<para>Chasidei Umot haOlam is a stage in a good process that one must strive to move forward
		from. Kosher animals also emanate from klipat nogah, which is the same source as Chasidei
		Umot haOlam. Both Chasidei Umot haOlam and kosher animals have the potential to be elevated
		in self-sacrifice, or the potential to be used for impurity - treif.</para>
	<para>When a Chasid Umot haOlam learns about and begins to unify haShem, one can start to say
		the Shema with proper kavanah. That person is now FROM the Chasidei Umot haOlam and enter
		into a different category. This is a formula for rejecting shituf. (see the CHIDA's
		interaction with the non-Jew written in the CHIDA's journal, where he instructs a non-Jew to
		say Shema and reject shituf)</para>
	<para>May it be that all the Chasidei Umot haOlam be brought to achdus haShem and we serve
		haShem in fellowship by saying Shema and Aleinu, together.</para>
	<para>Because <emphasis>Chassidei Umot haOlam</emphasis> are <emphasis>bnei Noach</emphasis>, they
		may give a burnt offering.</para>
	<para><emphasis>Chassidei Umot haOlam</emphasis> are worthy of the crown of Torah. Teffilin is a
		personal crown of Torah.</para>
	<para><emphasis>Chassidei Umot haOlam</emphasis> have animal souls that emanate from
			<emphasis>klipat nogah</emphasis>. <emphasis>Klipot nogah</emphasis> contains a mixture
		of good and evil and is the same place where <emphasis>bnei Yisrael</emphasis> animal souls
		and clean animal souls originate. </para>
	<para>Chasidei Umot haOlam are still under the service of shituf. Only through achdus haShem
		and/or saying kriat Shema with kevana can one come out from shituf.<footnote><para>תפילת שחרית לחול, Likutei ha'Gra, Kriat Shema</para></footnote></para>
	<para>It appears to me that it may be <emphasis>Chassidei Umot haOlam</emphasis> that do more
		than the <emphasis>sheva mitzvot haShem</emphasis> are like ones that do
			<emphasis>mitzvot</emphasis> but are not commanded, similar to <emphasis>bnei Noach
			stam</emphasis> that do and are not commanded.</para>
	<para>He granted the nations a divine soul, like the souls of <emphasis>bnei Yisrael</emphasis>,
		but not on the level of <emphasis>bnei Yisrael</emphasis> - Derech haShem, RAMCHAL,
		Hebrew-English 139-141, Israel and the Nations. <emphasis>Chassidei Umot haOlam</emphasis>
		are a garment to <emphasis>Israel</emphasis>. - RAMCHAL It appears to me, from Tanya,
		Likutei Amarim Ch. 10-11 and Shulchan Aruch haRav, Washing of Hands, that the Divine/Holy
		soul the <emphasis>Shechinah</emphasis> is removed and hovers above a <emphasis>Chasid Umot
			haOlam</emphasis> waiting for the removal of klipah so that she can descend and rest
		upon the soul of such a person. This is most likely why the RITVA who is quoted form the
		Avodah Berurah on Avodah Zara 64b, says concerning the ger toshav(who is also Chasidei Umot
		haOlam according to Rambam Hilchot Issurei Biah 14:7-8) that he is "a little converted". In
		other words, he has begun his ger'ing and is interacting with the
			<emphasis>Shechinah</emphasis> similar to a Jewish baby boy. Upon accepting
			<emphasis>Torah</emphasis>, a new soul/level is given.<footnote>
			<para>Derech haShem, Part 2, Chapter 4, commentaries</para>
		</footnote></para>
	<sect1>
		<title>History</title>
		<para>Pious means: use note text from R'Turen</para>
		<para>Umot means: peoples</para>
		<para>haOlam means: over the horizon</para>
		<para>Rav said: Avraham our Patriarch fulfilled the entire Torah, as it is stated: "Because
			Avraham hearkened to My voice and kept My charge, My mitzvot, My statutes and My Torahs"
			Gen 26:5. Rav Shimi bar Khiyya said to Rav: And say seven mitzvot(bnei Noach). But isn't
			there also circumcision? The Gemara says: and say the seven mitzvot and circumcision.
			Rav said to him: If so, why do I say Abraham kept: My mitzvot and my Torah? Rav said,
			and some say Rav Ashi said: Abraham our Patriarch fulfilled even the joining of cooked
			foods, as it is stated: My Torahs: Torah sheba'alpeh and Torah shebikhtav. - Yoma
			28b</para>
		<para>It appears to me that both opinions are correct and do not contradict. How could
				<emphasis>Avraham</emphasis> have kept <emphasis>mitzvot</emphasis> that were yet to
			be commanded? He did them through the <emphasis>Torah of Shem v'Ever</emphasis>.
				<emphasis>Avraham</emphasis> was the first <emphasis>ger</emphasis> through his
			acceptance of the mitzvah of circumcision.<footnote>
				<para>Chagigah 3a and Tosafos</para>
			</footnote></para>
		<para>The etymology of the words from the etymological dictionary.</para>
		<sect2>
			<title>The God-Fearers </title>
			<blockquote><para>“The history of Jews in North Africa, according to the Jewish historian Josephus,
				began with the 30,000 Jews exiled to Carthage by Titus after he conquered Jerusalem
				(70 CE). From the second century ce there is historical documentation attesting to
				the conversion of Libyan, Carthaginian,and other North Africa natives to Judaism.
				Some of these became full proselytes, others merely observed part of the Jewish
				precepts and became “fearers of Heaven” [i.e. Noahides] such as we have already met.
				Since under the Roman emperors Septimus Severus and his son Marcus Aurelius
				Antoninus (nicknamed Caracalla) Judaism was a “licit” religion, while Christianity
				was not, many pagans who were attracted to Christianity converted to Judaism in
				order to be able to become secret Christians. The bitter denunciation of Judaism by
				Tertullian must be understood as stemming from North African Christians
				theologians’ire over the success of Judaism in attracting such proselytes.</para>
			<para>Almost two centuries later, St.Augustine refers to the great number of converts to
				Judaism among the Christians of the Byzantine Province (Central Tunisia). The
				poet-bishop Commodianus, who was North African origin and lived within the third or
				fourth centuries or, according to others, in the fifth century, wrote several
				satirical poems against the Jews,and the pagans who converted to Judaism.</para>
			<para>In the last century prior to the Arab invasion of North Africa, both Christianity
				and Judaism made considerable headway among the Berber Tribes. One of the leading
				tribes among the Zenata group of the Berbers was the Jewish Jarawa,headed by a woman
				queen named Dahya al-Kahinna (the Seeress), who dealt a crushing defeat to the
				Muslim Arab general Hasan ibn Nu’man in the late seventh century, only to be
				defeated in turn several years later by a coalition of Muslim Arab and Christian
				forces. Tradition has it that she was 125 or 127 years old when she was
				killed(perhaps a reminiscence of the 127 years of the life of Sarah), and that she
				had ruled the Berbers for thirty-five or sixty-five years.</para>
			<para>On the basis of admittedly scanty historical data, most scholars have formed that
				opinion that most of the Jews of North Africa are of Berber origin.”</para></blockquote>
			<para>‘The Myth of the Jewish Race’ by Raphael Patai, Jennifer Patai Pg. 66</para>
			<para>Mention the "God-Fearers" of the Christian NT.</para>
			<para>God-Fearers are also the fourth house of Israel(Tehillim 135:20) .</para>
		</sect2>
	</sect1>
</chapter>
