<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<chapter id="bnei_noach">
	<title>Children of Noah</title>
	<subtitle>בני נח - Bnei Noach</subtitle>
	<para><emphasis>Bnei Noach</emphasis> are also <emphasis>Umot haOlam.</emphasis><footnoteref linkend="Nedarim_31a"/></para>
	<para><emphasis>Avraham</emphasis> had the <emphasis>din</emphasis> of <emphasis>Ben
			Noach</emphasis>,<footnote id="LS_Vol_5_page_157">
			<para>Likutei Sichot, Volume 5, page 157?(see Rabbi Turen's audio. It says
				explicitly)</para>
		</footnote> yet, he kept the whole <emphasis>Torah</emphasis>, even its minutiae.<footnote id="Talmud_Bavli_Yoma_28">
			<para>Talmud Bavli, Misechet Yoma 28</para>
		</footnote></para>
	<para>Talk about the different stages of marriage. What stage is significant and where is the
			<emphasis>kavanah</emphasis>.</para>
	<para>Talk about the <emphasis>Yafat Toar</emphasis>.</para>
	<para>Talk about how <emphasis>bnei Noach</emphasis> are like women in Torah. They may are
		expected to do negative commandments, but not expected to do positive commandments. Negative
		Commandments are passive and not active. Negative commandments stem from the fear of
			<emphasis>haShem</emphasis>.</para>
	<para>
		<emphasis>Yisrael</emphasis> is a priestly nation. A priest is not a priest without those to
		intercede for. A king is not a king without a queen.</para>
	<para>A bride must be pure. The <emphasis>Shechinah</emphasis> cannot dwell with impurity.
		Keeping the <emphasis>seven mitzvot bnei Noach</emphasis> purifies the midot of a
		person.</para>
	<para>There is an arousal from above, which is the first time <emphasis>ben Yisrael</emphasis>
		comes to the <emphasis>yafat toar</emphasis> in her impurity. He cannot be with her again
		until she is pure, which she must do herself: that is an arousal from below where she
		accepts to be a <emphasis>ger tzedek</emphasis> or a <emphasis>ger toshav</emphasis>. The
		receiver is feminine and the giver is masculine: much like intercourse.</para>
	<para><emphasis>Bnei Noach</emphasis> are the children of Noah. <emphasis>haShem
			Elokim</emphasis> commanded all <emphasis>bnei Noach</emphasis> to keep the
			<emphasis>sheva mitzvot bnei Noach</emphasis>. The rainbow is a sign of that covenant.
		It's an eternal covenant. As long as a society keeps to the covenant, <emphasis>haShem
			Elokim</emphasis> will not destroy that society.</para>
	<para>All of humanity are <emphasis>bnei Noach</emphasis>. <emphasis>Bnei Yisrael</emphasis> has
		a distinction from the merit of Avraham and are not classified as <emphasis>bnei
			Noach</emphasis> even though technically they are also descended from Noah.
			<emphasis>Goyim</emphasis>, even though technically still <emphasis>bnei
			Noach</emphasis>, are idolaters.<footnote id="Nedarim_31a">
			<para>Nedarim 31a</para>
		</footnote></para>
	<para>It appears to me, that just as <emphasis>minim</emphasis> are still <emphasis>bnei
			Yisrael</emphasis>, <emphasis>goyim</emphasis> are still <emphasis>bnei
		Noach</emphasis>. But just like <emphasis>minim</emphasis> have special
			<emphasis>halachot</emphasis> they must follow as exceptions and be treated as an
		exception, so to <emphasis>goyim</emphasis> must follow exceptions and be treated as an
		exception. A <emphasis>goy</emphasis> is to <emphasis>bnei Noach</emphasis> as a
			<emphasis>min</emphasis> is to <emphasis>bnei Yisrael</emphasis>.</para>
	<para>Therefore, whenever the term <emphasis>bnei Noach</emphasis> is used, this is referring to
		those that are not <emphasis>bnei Yisrael</emphasis>. I currently do not know if
			<emphasis>gerim</emphasis> are <emphasis>bnei Noach</emphasis>. I don't think they are,
		since a <emphasis>ger toshav</emphasis> is no longer a part of the <emphasis>amim</emphasis>
		per L"S, Mishpatim Beis footnote 74-ish. <emphasis>Gerim</emphasis> are attached to
			<emphasis>bnei Yisrael</emphasis> and are described as being part of <emphasis>klal
			Yisrael</emphasis>. It appears to me that <emphasis>gerim</emphasis> would then also be
		from the merit of <emphasis>Avraham</emphasis> and set apart with with <emphasis>bnei
			Yisrael</emphasis> as <emphasis>bnei Avraham</emphasis>.<footnoteref
			linkend="Nedarim_31a"/> This may only be when a <emphasis>ger</emphasis> circumcises
		himself that he becomes <emphasis>bnei Avraham</emphasis> and able to eat of the lamb of
			<emphasis>Pesach</emphasis>. See also Divine Providence in Derech haShem where it talks
		about grafting out of the branches of the <emphasis>amim</emphasis> and into the branch of
			<emphasis>Avraham</emphasis>. Hilchot Nedarim 9:23 and Yoma 66a implies that whenever
			<emphasis>Israel</emphasis> is plainly mentioned, it is referring to
			<emphasis>gerim</emphasis>, <emphasis>bnei Yisrael</emphasis>,
			<emphasis>kohanim</emphasis>, and <emphasis>levi'im</emphasis>.<footnote>
			<para>Tehillim 16:5</para>
		</footnote>
		<emphasis>Gerim</emphasis> are the fourth house of <emphasis>Yisrael</emphasis>.<footnote>
			<para>Sifrei Devarim 23:3 "The Kehilot"</para>
		</footnote></para>
	<para><emphasis>Bnei Noach</emphasis> may give the holiest of offerings; the burnt offering. The
		burnt offering is the only offering they may give as <emphasis>bnei Noach</emphasis> proper.
		It appears to me, that this is because once <emphasis>bnei Noach</emphasis> give a proper
		burnt offering, they enter a new status as a <emphasis>ger</emphasis>, which is someone who
		is now sojourning into a relationship with <emphasis>haShem</emphasis>.</para>
	<para><emphasis>Bnei Noach</emphasis> may or may not emanate from <emphasis>klipot
			nogah</emphasis>. If <emphasis>bnei Noach</emphasis> keep the <emphasis>sheva mitzvot
			bnei Noach</emphasis> for any other reason than for the sake of heaven, they emanate not
		from <emphasis>klipot nogah</emphasis>, but rather from the three impure
			<emphasis>klipot</emphasis> where no good exists. They then do not receive a portion in
			<emphasis>Olam haBah</emphasis>. However, if <emphasis>bnei Noach</emphasis> keep the
			<emphasis>sheva mitzvot bnei Noach</emphasis> for the sake of Heaven, they emanate from
			<emphasis>klipot nogah</emphasis> where there is good and evil. They do receive a
		portion in <emphasis>Olam haBa</emphasis>. One must be attached to the Source of
			<emphasis>Olam haBa</emphasis>.</para>
	<para><emphasis>Bnei Noach</emphasis> are made in the image of <emphasis>haShem
			Elokim</emphasis>:Tosephos YomTov on Avos 3:14 in explanation of the saying of Rabbi
		Akiva in the Mishna there "beloved is Man who is created in the Divine Image" as this was
		also said with reference to Bnai Noach - and according to what the Rambam writes in the Laws
		of Kings. See there.</para>
	<para>Not only can <emphasis>bnei Noach</emphasis> do more<footnote><para>Rambam, Hilchot Melachim 10:10</para></footnote><footnote><para>A goy/a"kum/nochri is prohibited from orlah. However, if a nochri desires to observe the mitzvah of neta reva'i, it's laws apply to him and it is consecrated like neta reva'i of a Yisrael.
		- Rambam, Mishneh Torah, Neta Riva'i 10:10</para></footnote>(although not mandatory),  <emphasis>bnei
			Noach</emphasis> are also halachically separate than the <emphasis>goy
		stam</emphasis>(plain goy)(Hilchot Melachim 10:10) who is an idolator(A"KUM)(Hilchot
		Ma'achalot Assurot 11:8). They are different <emphasis>dea’ot</emphasis> - containers of
		logic. It's clear in the juxtaposition from <emphasis>Hilchot Melachim 10:10</emphasis> that
		the <emphasis>ben Noach</emphasis> and <emphasis>goy</emphasis> are two different types of entities.<footnote>
			<para>If a <emphasis>ben Noach</emphasis> who observes the <emphasis>sheva mitzvot bnei
					Noach</emphasis> gives charity, we should accept it from him. It appears to me
				that it should be given to the Jewish poor for the ben Noach may derive his
				sustenance from the Jews and they are commanded to support him if necessary. In
				contrast, if a goy gives charity, we should accept it from him and give it to the
				goy poor." - Rambam, Hilchot Melachim 10:10 (from the Yemenite unedited)</para>
		</footnote></para>
	<sidebar>
		<para>Not only can bnei Noach do more, although not mandatory, bnei Noach are also
			halachically separate than the goy stam(plain goy) who is an idolator(A"KUM). They are
			different dea’ot.</para>
	</sidebar>
	<para>Every Jew in these times can teach the <emphasis>sheva mitzvot bnei Noach</emphasis>
		because Hilchot Melachim 8:10 says to.<footnote>
			<para><emphasis>Likutei Sichos</emphasis> Vol 26, 3rd <emphasis>Parshas
				Yitro</emphasis></para>
		</footnote>It also says that every Jew should <emphasis>lakuf</emphasis>(strongly compel)
		non-Jews to keep the seven or kill the non-Jew if he doesn't. Therefore, the Jew has the
		ability in these times to determine who is the <emphasis>ben Noach</emphasis> and who is the
			<emphasis>goy</emphasis>. Therefore, <emphasis>Hilchot Melachim</emphasis> 10:10 applies
		in these times and a Jew can determine who the Jew has a <emphasis>mitzvah
			l'hichuto</emphasis> (to sustain the livelyhood, both spiritually and physically, in a
		time of need of the <emphasis>ben Noach</emphasis> that gives
		<emphasis>tzedekah</emphasis>). This is the <emphasis>k'ger toshav</emphasis> of today. The
		Jew <emphasis>mitzvah l'hichuto</emphasis> to sustain the <emphasis>ben Noach</emphasis>
		that gives tzedekah and that <emphasis>ben Noach</emphasis> can do
			<emphasis>mitzvot</emphasis>.<footnote>
			<para><emphasis>Rambam, Hilchot Melachim</emphasis> 10:10</para>
		</footnote></para>
	<para>A <emphasis>ben Noach</emphasis> can involve himself in any part of Torah(Chasam Sofer,
		Sheva Mitzvot haShem pg. 105)</para>
	<sect1>
		<title>History</title>
		<para>This History of the <emphasis>bnei Noach</emphasis></para>
	</sect1>
	<sect1>
		<title>Halacha</title>
		<sect2>
			<title>No Eating the Limb of a Live Animal</title>
			<para>No Eating Limbs of a Live Animal</para>
		</sect2>
		<sect2>
			<title>No Murder</title>
			<para>No Murder</para>
			<para>May not flee to a city of refuge. <emphasis>Bnei Yisrael</emphasis> will not
				receive him.</para>
		</sect2>
		<sect2>
			<title>No Stealing</title>
			<para>No Stealing</para>
		</sect2>
		<sect2>
			<title>No Blasphemy</title>
			<para>No Blasphemy</para>
		</sect2>
		<sect2>
			<title>No Strange Worship</title>
			<para>No Strange Worship</para>
		</sect2>
		<sect2>
			<title>No Illicit Relationships</title>
			<para>No Illicit Relationships</para>
		</sect2>
		<sect2>
			<title>No Failure to Establish a Court</title>
			<para>No Failure to Establish a Court</para>
		</sect2>
	</sect1>
	<sect1>
		<title>Responsa</title>
		<para><emphasis role="bold">Statement:</emphasis> The <emphasis>bnei Noach</emphasis> must
			stay <emphasis>bnei Noach</emphasis></para>
		<para><emphasis role="bold">Response:</emphasis>
			<emphasis>Bnei Noach</emphasis> can give the holiest of offerings, the burnt offering,
			which is an action of total submission and transformation</para>
	</sect1>
</chapter>
