<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<chapter id="goy">
	<title>Goy</title>
	<para>You've probably heard the term <emphasis>goy</emphasis> used in reference to
		non-Jews.</para>
	<para>Colloquially, the term <emphasis>goy</emphasis> is used to refer to a non-Jew. However,
		students of <emphasis>Torah</emphasis> generally do not care too much for modern
		colloquiallisms in their studies. Therefore, we will not be referring to this type of
			<emphasis>goy</emphasis>. Instead, we will be referrring to the <emphasis>goy</emphasis>
		found in <emphasis>Torah</emphasis>. This is the <emphasis>goy stam</emphasis> - the plain
			<emphasis>goy</emphasis>.</para>
	<para>In <emphasis>Torah shebikhtav</emphasis>, the term <emphasis>goy</emphasis> seems to have a
		neutral connotation, where any negativity toward <emphasis>goy</emphasis> would be implied.
		This may not actually be true, but it seems that way. However, it seems during the time of
		the Prophets and Writings, <emphasis>goyim</emphasis> started getting a bad wrap for being
		primarily idol worshippers. This connotation carried over into the <emphasis>Torah
			sheba'alpeh</emphasis>, where <emphasis>goyim</emphasis> as idolaters were solidified.
		It is only with other qualifiers that <emphasis>goy</emphasis> changes its idolater
		status.</para>
	<para>The implications of using the vulgar definition of <emphasis>goy</emphasis> are critical
		and highly negative. It's the cause of baseless hatred between Jew and non-Jew alike. It's
		imperative to the redemption that we should be constantly refining and purifying our speech.<footnote>
			<para>Zephaniah 3:9</para>
		</footnote></para>
	<para>There also seems to be a difference between the usage of <emphasis>goy</emphasis> versus
			<emphasis>goyim</emphasis>. The <emphasis>R"AMCHAL</emphasis> states that the collective
			<emphasis>goyim</emphasis> cannot be transformed while individual
			<emphasis>goy</emphasis> can and he can be grafted into the trunk of
			<emphasis>Avraham</emphasis>. Also, it says <emphasis>Avraham</emphasis> is the father
		of <emphasis>goyim</emphasis>.</para>
	<sect1>
		<title><emphasis>Goy</emphasis> and <emphasis>Am</emphasis>: The Difference</title>
		<para>The words <emphasis>goy</emphasis> and <emphasis>am</emphasis> are usually both translated
			as "people" or "nation" and are seemingly interchangeable. However, that doesn't seem to
			be the case every time. <emphasis>Goy</emphasis> seems to denote something akin to
			culture and way of life and a common king. <emphasis>Am</emphasis> seems to denote
			physical groups of people that live and interact with one another, but do not have a
			common king. <emphasis>Bnei Yisrael</emphasis> is referred to as a holy
				<emphasis>goy</emphasis>; often translated as <emphasis>holy nation</emphasis>. -
			הכרמל - מלבים, מאיר ליבוש, 1809-1879</para>
	</sect1>
	<sect1>
		<title>History</title>
		<para>This History of the <emphasis>goy</emphasis></para>
		<para>The etymology of the word from the etymological dictionary</para>
	</sect1>
	<sect1>
		<title>Halacha</title>
		<para>Halachah for the <emphasis>goy</emphasis></para>
		<para>There is no non-Jew so lowely as the <emphasis>goy</emphasis>. It can then be
			logically implied that this not a respected or honored status for non-Jews and something
			you would want to not be of.</para>
		<para>Whenever halacha mentions the <emphasis>goy</emphasis> without any other qualifiers, it is
			referring to the idolater.<footnote>
				<para>R"ITVA on Makos 9a</para>
			</footnote><footnote>
				<para>Chatam Sofer on Sanhedrin</para>
			</footnote><footnote>
				<para>Hullin 13a</para>
				<para> </para>
			</footnote><footnote>
				<para>"The unspecified intentions of a <emphasis>goy</emphasis> is for
					idol-worship"</para>
				<para>סתם מחשבת גוי לעבודה זרה</para>
				<para> Rabbi Eliezer, Talmud Bavli, Gittin 45b</para>
				<para> </para>
			</footnote><footnote>
				<para>"Wherever we write '<emphasis>goy</emphasis>' without any further qualifiers,
					we are referring to the worshipper of idols" - Rambam, Mishneh Torah, Ma'achalot
					Assurot 11:8</para>
				<para>Some say that this citation is referring to only the context of wine. It's
					true that this is referring to the context of wine, but not regarding the
						<emphasis>goy</emphasis>. It's referring to the usage of the words
					"forbidden" and "permitted", which in the context of wine are both related to
					drinking from wine, which can be permitted or forbidden, and/or from benefitting
					from wine, whether permitted or forbidden. Rambam often writes in incomplete
					sentences, much like an outline, so Rambam is trying to clarify here. Also, this
					definition of goy only within the context of wine would contradict the Chazal
					definition of goy.</para>
			</footnote> Whenever the term <emphasis>goy</emphasis> is plainly mentioned in
				<emphasis>halachah</emphasis> without any other qualifiers, it's referring to the
			idol worshipper. <emphasis>Goy</emphasis> is different than a <emphasis>ben
				Noach</emphasis> or a <emphasis>ger toshav</emphasis>.<footnote>
				<para>Soloveitchik, Od Yisrael Yoseph Bni Chai, Siyum 7</para>
				<para> </para>
			</footnote><footnote>
				<para>Sanhedrin 59</para>
				<para> </para>
			</footnote><footnote>
				<para> Meiri, Bet Habechirah, Avodah Zarah, 53 It has already been stated that these
					things [laws relating to gentiles] were said concerning periods when there
					existed nations of idolaters, and they were contaminated in their deeds and
					tainted in their dispositions . . . but other nations, which are restrained by
					the ways of religion and which are free from such blemishes of character – on
					the contrary, they even punish such deeds – are, without doubt, exempt from this
					prohibition. ]לח[ מאירי, בית הבחירה ע"ז כב, א וכבר התבאר שדברים הללו נאמרו לאותם
					הזמנים שהיו אותם האומות מעובדי האלילים והיו מזוהמים במעשיהם ומכעורים במדותיהם .
					. . אבל שאר אומות שהם גדורים בדרכי הדתות ושהם נקיים מכעורים שבמדות הללו ואדרבה
					שמענישים עליהם אין ספק שאין הדברים הללו מקום להם כלל.</para>
			</footnote><footnote>
				<para>[39] Be’er haGolah to Choshen Mishpat 425:5. The rabbis of the Talmud meant by
					the term ‘idolators’ the pagans who lived in their time, who worshipped the
					stars and the constellations and did not believe in the Exodus from Egypt and in
					the creation of the world out of nothing. But the nations under whose benevolent
					shadow we, the Jewish nation, are exiled and are dispersed among them, they do
					believe in the creation of the world out of nothing and the Exodus from Egypt
					and in the essentials of faith, and their whole intention is toward the Maker of
					heaven and earth, as other authorities have said . . . these nations do believe
					in all of this. ]לט[ באר הגולה, חושן משפט תכה:ה לא אמרו חז"ל דבר זה אלא על
					העכו"ם שהיו בזמניהם שהיו עודי כוכבים ומזלות ולא היו מאמינים ביציאת מצרים ובחדוש
					העולם, אבל אלו הגוים אשר אנחנו, ואמה ישראלים, חוסים בצל שלהם ומפוזרים ביניהם, הם
					מאמינים בחידוש העולם וביציאת מצרים ובעקרי הדת, וכל כוונתם לעושה שמים וארץ, כמ"ש
					הפוסקים . . . הם מאמינים בכל אלה.</para>
			</footnote>Other peoples are definitely <emphasis>goyim</emphasis> as well, but have
			qualifiers. Bnei Yisrael is a good example; they are referred to as <emphasis>goy
				kadosh</emphasis>. Kadosh is the qualifer and thus this is not referring to the
			idol-worshipper. This is a common confusion point where many people will say that "goy"
			is just a general term. Rambam is explicitly taking the generality out of the equation
			to let the reader know he is explicitly refering to an idolater. Talmud Bavli, Gittin
			45b, Rabbi Eliezer says an unspecified <emphasis>goy</emphasis> is treated like an
			idol-worshipper.</para>
		<para>The beginning of <emphasis>goy</emphasis> as a term for idolaters is mentioned
				<emphasis>midrash</emphasis>, where <emphasis>goyim</emphasis> are <emphasis>bnei
				Noach</emphasis> that do not follow the <emphasis>sheva mitzvot bnei
				Noach</emphasis> closely<footnote>
				<para>Hilchot Avodah Zarah 1</para>
			</footnote> and then for a second time during <emphasis>matan Torah</emphasis>. During
			this second time in rejection of <emphasis>Torah</emphasis>, the wealth of
				<emphasis>goyim</emphasis> are given to <emphasis>bnei Yisrael</emphasis>.<footnote>
				<para>Bava Kama 38</para>
			</footnote>.</para>
		<para>The acceptance of a <emphasis>goy</emphasis> by the CHIDA's(Azulai) grandson is noted in his
			journal, where he interrogates a <emphasis>goy</emphasis> and tell him to recite Shema
			every morning. It turns out, he is not a <emphasis>goy</emphasis> but at least a
				<emphasis>ben Noach</emphasis>. It appears to me he is the <emphasis>ben
				Noach</emphasis> of <emphasis>Hilchot Melachim 10:10</emphasis>.</para>
		<para>A <emphasis>goy</emphasis> can work the land during a <emphasis>Shemita</emphasis> year.<footnote>
				<para>Hilchot Shemita 8:8</para>
				<para> </para>
			</footnote></para>
		<para>King David accepted the nochri and made him one of his lieutenants.</para>
		<para>There are two main types of <emphasis>Torah</emphasis> study: <emphasis>lamud</emphasis> and
				<emphasis>osek</emphasis>. <emphasis>Lamud</emphasis> is cursory study you do to
			just memorize and know the thing that you're learning. <emphasis>Osek</emphasis> is when
			you completely lose yourself in the study and digest what you're learning on a very deep
			level. In <emphasis>osek</emphasis> type of study, you are completely involved. You are
			constantly thinking about a thing, concept, idea, verse, etc. A <emphasis>goy</emphasis>
			cannot <emphasis>osek</emphasis> himself in complete <emphasis>Torah</emphasis> study. A
				<emphasis>goy</emphasis> can only <emphasis>osek</emphasis> in the <emphasis>sheva
				mitzvot bnei Noach</emphasis>. He can, however, <emphasis>lamud</emphasis> in any
			aspects of <emphasis>Torah</emphasis>. A <emphasis>goy</emphasis> can even
				<emphasis>osek</emphasis>
			<emphasis>Chassidut</emphasis>.<caution>
				<para>Plain <emphasis>goy</emphasis> without any further description refers to the
					idol-worshipper by default. This causes huge problems in texts about the non-Jew
					in <emphasis>Torah</emphasis>. A lot of those texts cite
						<emphasis>halachah</emphasis>  concerning <emphasis>goy</emphasis>, which
					causes huge confusion for a reader who might instead be a <emphasis>ben
						Noach</emphasis> or <emphasis>bat Noach</emphasis>.</para>
			</caution></para>
		<para>It is forbidden for a <emphasis>Jew</emphasis> to teach his <emphasis>eved</emphasis>
			<emphasis>Torah</emphasis>.<footnote>
				<para>Hilchot Avadim 8:18</para>
				<para> </para>
			</footnote> However, Rabban Gamliel described his servant Tavi as a Torah scholar.<footnote>
				<para>Sukkah 20b</para>
				<para> </para>
			</footnote> This seems like a contradiction. In my opinion, this seems to suggest the
			initiative and <emphasis>kavanah</emphasis> must come from the non-Jew.</para>
		<para>A <emphasis>goy</emphasis> cannot involve himself in Torah except for the <emphasis>sheva
				mitzvot bnei Noach</emphasis> and he cannot keep shabbat. It's assumed if he
			involves himself in Torah, the <emphasis>goy</emphasis> will use it for <emphasis>avodah
				zarah</emphasis>.<footnote>
				<para>Sanhedrin 59</para>
				<para> </para>
			</footnote> He cannot even rest or take time to rest. He may not create holidays for
			himself. </para>
		<para>It's assumed the <emphasis>goy</emphasis> commits idolatry.</para>
		<para>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>And the Gemara explained:</para>
					<para>"An ox of a Jew which gores an ox of a Canaanite is exempt." They say:
						whichever way you turn -- if "his neighbor" is meant specifically, an ox of
						a Canaanite which gores an ox of a Jew should also be exempt; if "his
						neighbor" is not meant specifically, an ox of a Jew which gores an ox of a
						Canaanite should also be liable. Rabbi Abahu said: it is written, "He stood
						and measured the earth; He beheld and drove asunder the nations" -- [God]
						saw that the Sons of Noah [Gentiles] were not fulfilling the Seven
						Commandments they accepted upon themselves, and permitted their property to
						the Jews. Rabbi Jochanan said, it is learnt from here: "He appeared from
						Mount Paran" -- from Mount Paran [the Giving of the Torah] their property
						was permitted to the Jews.</para>
					<para>(Bava Kama 38a)</para>
					<para>To which the Meiri added:</para>
					<blockquote>
						<para>According to what is said in the Gemara, this law applies only to the
							nations which are not restricted by ways of religions and customs, as
							the Gemara said of them, "[God] saw that the Sons of Noah [non-Jews]
							were not fulfilling the Seven Commandments they accepted upon
							themselves, so He permitted their property to the Jews," as long as they
							are obliged by these commandments -- therefore, those [non-Jews] who
							fulfill the Seven Commandments should be treated by us as we are treated
							by them, and we should not favor ourselves in judgment; now it is
							unnecessary to specify that this is also the case concerning the nations
							restricted by ways of religions and customs.</para>
						<para>(Beit ha-Bechirah on Bava Kama 37b)</para>
					</blockquote>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</para>
		<para>Research Hilchot Avodah Zarah and see if we see the creation of
				<emphasis>goyim</emphasis> during the time of <emphasis>Enosh</emphasis>.</para>
		<sect2>
			<title>Shabbat Goy</title>
			<para>Shabbat Goy - Tosefot citation -
				http://judaism.stackexchange.com/questions/62268/can-a-gentile-volunteer-to-perform-prohibited-actions-on-behalf-of-a-jew-on-shab?rq=1</para>
			<para>A <emphasis>ben Noach</emphasis> can refrain from <emphasis>Shabbat
					melakim</emphasis> however he sees fit. This <emphasis>ben Noach</emphasis>
				should not do <emphasis>Shabbat melakim</emphasis> for the Jew. <footnote>
					<para><emphasis>Sichos</emphasis> Volume 31, <emphasis>Parshas
							Mishpatim</emphasis>, Section 5</para>
					<para> </para>
				</footnote></para>
		</sect2>
		<sect2>
			<title>Goy and A"KUM Equivalence</title>
			<para>The noun <emphasis>goy</emphasis> and the acronym <emphasis>a"kum</emphasis> are
				equivalent in <emphasis>halachah</emphasis>. This is proven multiple places. One way
				of proof, is when halacha says <emphasis>a"kum</emphasis> and then quotes
					<emphasis>Torah</emphasis> where it says <emphasis>goy</emphasis>(Nedarim
				9:22).</para>
		</sect2>
	</sect1>
	<sect1>
		<title>Responsa</title>
		<para><emphasis role="bold">Statement:</emphasis> The <emphasis>goy</emphasis> means all
			non-Jews</para>
		<para><emphasis role="bold">Response:</emphasis> The <emphasis>goy</emphasis> is different
			than other non-Jews. For example the <emphasis>goy</emphasis> cannot give charity to the
				<emphasis>bnei Yisrael</emphasis> and have a poor <emphasis>bne Yisrael</emphasis>
			accept it. However, a <emphasis>ben Noach</emphasis> who keeps the <emphasis>sheva
				mitzvot bnei Noach</emphasis> can give charity and it is received. Therefore,
				<emphasis>goyim</emphasis> and <emphasis>bnei Noach</emphasis> are not the
			same.</para>
		<para><emphasis role="bold">Statement:</emphasis> The <emphasis>goy</emphasis> is a superset
			of non-Jews</para>
	</sect1>
</chapter>
